<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Genetic Preservation Archives | Viagen Pets</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.viagenpets.com/category/genetic-preservation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/category/genetic-preservation/</link>
	<description>Love the lasts forever</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 21:19:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>I Want Pet Cloning For My Sick Pet</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/pet-cloning-for-my-sick-pet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 15:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genetic Preservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pet cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pet cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pet genetic preservation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Considering Pet Cloning for A Sick Pet Pet cloning and pet genetic preservation are two options that are now available to pet owners who have sick dogs or cats and might be approaching the end of their lives.  These situations can be heartbreaking for pet parents. We cherish the time we have with them as a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/pet-cloning-for-my-sick-pet/">I Want Pet Cloning For My Sick Pet</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family: 'Calibri',sans-serif; font-size: 11pt;"><!--?xml:namespace prefix = "o" /--></span></p>
<h1>Considering Pet Cloning for A Sick Pet</h1>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-2351" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Blog-photo-09212016.jpg" alt="pet dog paw with human hand" width="600" height="305" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Blog-photo-09212016.jpg 660w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Blog-photo-09212016-300x152.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p>Pet cloning and pet genetic preservation are two options that are now available to pet owners who have sick dogs or cats and might be approaching the end of their lives.  These situations can be heartbreaking for pet parents. We cherish the time we have with them as a puppy or kitten. We then continue to form that bond and build the relationship as they grow. Unfortunately, there is a point at the end of their lives, where we must part ways. Sometimes it’s unexpected, sometimes it is following an illness, but no matter the circumstances, it is never easy to say goodbye to a member of your family.</p>
<h2>The First Step is Pet Genetic Preservation<strong>          </strong></h2>
<p>During the last moments of your pet’s life, you may have begun searching for options and discovered media coverage of pet DNA preservation and <span style="color: #8f0e0e;"><a style="color: #8f0e0e;" href="https://viagenpets.com/dog-cloning/">pet cloning</a></span>.  In the situations where your pet is at the end of its life or has already passed, time is of the essence to help ensure your pet’s genetics can be successfully preserved.</p>
<p>Call a ViaGen Pets representative at 888-876-6104 to discuss the process and the steps to submitting tissue samples for preservation. There are emergency instructions that can be found <span style="color: #8f0e0e;"><a style="color: #8f0e0e;" href="https://viagenpets.com/emergency-pets/">here</a> </span>to assist your veterinarian in the collection and shipment of the tissue samples. These instructions will be helpful if your pet passes or the samples must be procured outside of office hours.</p>
<h2>How Does The Preservation Process Work?</h2>
<p>The cloning process begins with Genetic Preservation. Our Genetic Preservation service starts with skin punch biopsy samples taken by your veterinarian. We then culture those biopsy samples to generate new cell growth. It is those cells that we cryopreserve or freeze for long term storage. A small portion of them will be used in the future for the cloning process.</p>
<p>We recommend receiving the biopsy samples within 5 days of your pet’s passing, and your pet/tissue samples need to be kept at a refrigerated temperature (approximately 4ºC). Unfortunately with the current technology, we are not able to use other samples such as blood, hair, semen, or teeth for the cloning process.</p>
<h2>Working With You Through The Cell Culture Process</h2>
<p>We know this is a difficult time for you and your family, and we are here to discuss the process with you every step of the way. After working with your veterinarian to collect and ship the biopsy samples, we will contact you once the samples have arrived at our office, and we have started the cell culture process. We encourage you to contact us for updates on the progress of the cell culture after 1-2 weeks.</p>
<p>Once the culture is complete, we will communicate the number of cells that have been cryopreserved for your pet. On average, the culture process typically takes 4 weeks to be completed. We can then work with you to determine when moving forward with cloning is right for you and your family. By having preserved your precious pet’s genetics with us, you will have that option whether it is within the year or 10 years from now. You also have the option of simply keeping your pet’s cells cryopreserved with no commitment to move forward with the cloning process until you are ready. The cells will remain viable indefinitely.</p>
<h2>Being Ready For The Option of Pet Cloning</h2>
<p>Preserving your pet’s genetics won’t eliminate the grief that comes from their loss, but it may provide comfort in knowing you are honoring the memory of your beloved pet in this manner.  This crucial first step after the loss of a pet also gives you the option to consider pet cloning.  Many of our clients choose to clone their pets at a later date, well after their pet loss.  At the moment of grief they may not have been ready to make a final decision on cloning.  In this way, it&#8217;s easy to think of genetic preservation as providing as simply a prudent step that preserves options at a time that can be very stressful.</p>
<p>If you do decide to produce a genetic twin to your pet using the cloning process, it can also bring great joy to your family as you begin to make new memories with your happy, healthy puppy or kitten. The story of your lives, and the unique bond you have with your beloved pet is “to be continued.&#8221;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/pet-cloning-for-my-sick-pet/">I Want Pet Cloning For My Sick Pet</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#8217;s Not Unusual&#8230;Pet Cloning and GP Questions</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/its-not-unusual-pet-cloning-and-gp-questions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 15:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genetic Preservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pet cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frequently asked questions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2045</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Frequently Asked Pet Cloning and GP Questions We hear from many pet owners every day with questions about pet genetic preservation and cloning. Nearly every conversation we have starts with the owner saying “I’ve got an unusual question for you,&#8221; which isn’t a surprising preface for the questions we hear because pet genetic preservation and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/its-not-unusual-pet-cloning-and-gp-questions/">It&#8217;s Not Unusual&#8230;Pet Cloning and GP Questions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1><strong>Frequently Asked Pet Cloning and GP Questions</strong></h1>
<p>We hear from many pet owners every day with questions about pet genetic preservation and cloning. Nearly every conversation we have starts with the owner saying “I’ve got an unusual question for you,&#8221; which isn’t a surprising preface for the questions we hear because pet genetic preservation and cloning isn’t something that is talked about daily like the weather.</p>
<p>We understand that you’re calling because you have a deep bond and relationship with your special pet that you’d love to extend forever – if possible. So while the frequently asked <span style="color: #b30e0e;"><a style="color: #b30e0e;" href="https://viagenpets.com/faq/">pet cloning and pet genetic preservation questions</a></span> section of our website is a great resource for better understanding how pet genetic preservation and cloning works, here are a few of the most frequent questions we hear.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-2046" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/faqimage-300x188.png" alt="pet cloning pet genetic preservation frequently asked questions" width="550" height="344" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/faqimage-300x188.png 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/faqimage-1024x640.png 1024w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/faqimage-768x480.png 768w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/faqimage-360x225.png 360w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/faqimage.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>These Are NOT Unusual Questions&#8230;</h2>
<p><strong>“My pet is elderly or is in declining health, should I have the biopsy done while he or she is still living, or should I wait until they pass?”   </strong>This is completely your decision as a pet parent and also something you should consult with your veterinarian about since anesthesia (general or local) is necessary for the tissue biopsy needed from your pet. The tissue biopsy is the critical first step whether you want to simply preserve your pet’s genetics, or clone your special animal. We recommend that a tissue biopsy be done while your pet is alive and healthy. The biggest reason for this is that you will have the option to re-submit samples if the culture is not successful, which happens from time to time. If you wait to take a skin biopsy until your pet has passed away, and if the cell culture is not successful, it’s impossible to secure another skin biopsy.</p>
<p><strong>“Will my cloned pet look the same as the original, and will it have the same personality?”</strong> – Your cloned puppy or kitten will have the same coloring as the original, but the markings may not be in the same location. For example, if your dog is white and has a brown patch around his right eye, then your cloned puppy will be white but that brown patch could be located on the left eye. An exception to this is calico cats, with more information about them <span style="color: #b30e0e;"><a style="color: #b30e0e;" href="http://mentalfloss.com/article/66825/why-are-calico-cats-almost-always-female-and-always-look-different" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a></span>.</p>
<p><strong>“What happens if more than one kitten or puppy is born?”</strong> – Our contract states that if more than one cloned kitten or puppy is born in the litter you have the option of welcoming each of them into your home at no extra charge. If you are happy with just one, then we place any additional animals from the litter into a loving forever home.</p>
<p><strong>“My pet is sick with or has had (<u>ex: cancer</u>), does that mean the clone will have it as well?”. </strong>The simplified answer is this: if your pet has a genetics-rooted condition, and since a clone of your pet carries the identical genetic make-up as the original, then the cloned animal will likely carry the same condition. However, since many pet health conditions develop as a result of a combination of genetics <em>and</em> the environment, it’s difficult to be conclusive. We encourage you to consult your veterinarian to gain a deeper perspective on your pet’s specific condition.</p>
<p>“<strong>What is the cost of cloning my dog or cat?”</strong>    ViaGen Pets charges $50,000 for cat cloning and $50,000 for dogs. The cost does not differ based on the breed or size of your dog or cat. Payment for pet cloning is made in two installments; we ask for a 50% down payment at the time you sign your pet cloning contract, and collect the balance when you take delivery of your new kitten or puppy – which happens between 8 – 12 weeks after birth.  If you are undecided whether to proceed with cloning immediately, but don’t want to miss the opportunity later, that’s no problem. We recommend you do a genetic preservation now to preserve your pet’s cells. Once a genetic preservation is successful, those cells can be stored indefinitely.  So whether you decide to move on to cloning at a later date, or just want the peace of mind knowing your pet’s DNA has been preserved, genetic preservation is available for a cat or dog for $1,600.</p>
<p>We are here to answer any questions you have, and are just a phone call away!   Feel free to contact us at 888-876-6104. You can also submit an inquiry with your questions through our website and we will contact you.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/its-not-unusual-pet-cloning-and-gp-questions/">It&#8217;s Not Unusual&#8230;Pet Cloning and GP Questions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Is Pet Genetic Preservation?</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/what-is-pet-genetic-preservation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 20:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Genetic Preservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[genetic preservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pet genetic preservation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2036</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>An Intro to Pet Genetic Preservation Pet Genetic Preservation (GP) is the storing of an individual pet&#8217;s genetic material for later use. This is typically accomplished by freezing tissue, individual cells or germ plasma in liquid nitrogen (-186oC). Once stored in liquid nitrogen the sample will remain viable and can be stored indefinitely. At ViaGen Pets [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/what-is-pet-genetic-preservation/">What Is Pet Genetic Preservation?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 dir="LTR" align="LEFT">An Intro to Pet Genetic Preservation</h1>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT"><span style="color: #ab1d1d;"><a style="color: #ab1d1d;" href="https://viagenpets.com/product/genetic-preservation/">Pet Genetic Preservation</a></span> (GP) is the storing of an individual pet&#8217;s genetic material for later use. This is typically accomplished by freezing tissue, individual cells or germ plasma in liquid nitrogen (-186<sup>o</sup>C). Once stored in liquid nitrogen the sample will remain viable and can be stored indefinitely.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">At ViaGen Pets genetic preservation is available for dogs and cats and is often the first step towards cloning. Genetic preservation costs $1,600 and assures you that the genetic material or DNA of your pet is preserved in a viable and usable form.</p>
<h2 dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Start With A Biopsy Kit and Your Veterinarian</h2>
<div id="attachment_2037" style="width: 223px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2037" class="wp-image-2037 size-medium" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/kit-e1464032669355-213x300.jpg" alt="ViaGen Pets Genetic Preservation Biopsy Kit" width="213" height="300" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/kit-e1464032669355-213x300.jpg 213w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/kit-e1464032669355-300x423.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/kit-e1464032669355.jpg 354w" sizes="(max-width: 213px) 100vw, 213px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2037" class="wp-caption-text">ViaGen Pets Genetic Preservation Biopsy Kit</p></div>
<p>Once you contact ViaGen Pets to begin the genetic preservation process, a ViaGen Pets Biopsy Kit will be sent to you in order for your veterinarian to take a small biopsy from your pet. The Biopsy Kit includes instructions on how to take the biopsy.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Taking the biopsy is a simple and straight-forward process; however, we do recommend using your veterinarian. The process is safe for your pet and you can expect them to heal within a few days. The Biopsy Kit containing the tissue sample is then sent back to the ViaGen Pets cell culture center located in Cedar Park, TX. Upon arrival, the sample is sterilized and processed and cell growth is established. Following cell growth the cells will be counted and cryopreserved utilizing ViaGen Pet’s proprietary freezing process. Approximately 4 weeks from the start of the genetic preservation process the client will be contacted and informed of the overall number of cells frozen for the long-term storage of their pet’s DNA.</p>
<h2 dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Long-Term, Secure Genetic Material Storage</h2>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">The cryopreserved genetic material is then stored safely and securely at ViaGen Pets facilities; each is kept under lock and key and stored at two separate facilities. Throughout the process of genetic preservation, and as long as the genetic material is in storage at ViaGen Pets, the client remains the owner of their pet’s genetic material. The client makes all decisions about the cloning, transfer, culture or disposal of their pet’s genetic material. They may choose to go ahead with the cloning process or they may choose to wait until they feel the time is right.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Once you have taken advantage of genetic preservation for your pet you can be confident that your pet’s DNA is safely stored in a viable form for you to use now &#8212; or anytime in the future. Cryopreserved material has been used successfully after decades of storage.</p>
<h2 dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Preserving DNA of Deceased Pets</h2>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">In the unfortunate event your pet dies prior to doing a genetic preservation, timing and proper storage of tissue are key to successful cell growth for the genetic preservation process. It is essential that the tissue is kept refrigerated&#8211;not frozen&#8211;prior to taking the biopsy, and the biopsy should be taken as soon as possible by your pet’s veterinarian. Contact ViaGen Pets right away for more information and proper guidance.</p>
<h2 dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Express Tissue Banking</h2>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT"><span style="color: #ab1d1d;"><a style="color: #ab1d1d;" href="https://viagenpets.com/product/express-tissue-banking/">Express Tissue Banking</a></span> (ETB) is another cryopreservation service offered by ViaGen Pets for your dog or cat. Once you contact ViaGen Pets for Express Tissue Bank services, a Biopsy Kit will be sent with the instructions and tools necessary for your pet’s veterinarian to take a biopsy. As with Genetic Preservation, the biopsy is a safe and simple process and your pet will fully heal in a short time. Express Tissue Bank differs from genetic preservation in that the tissue biopsy itself is cryopreserved, but the cells are not cultured from the biopsy for cryopreservation. Because cells are not cultured from the original biopsy prior to cryopreservation, it is not guaranteed that viable cells for cloning can be produced. However, you can feel secure that your pet’s genetic material is preserved.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/what-is-pet-genetic-preservation/">What Is Pet Genetic Preservation?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are Veterinarians Involved in Genetically Preserving and Cloning My Pet?</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/are-veterinarians-involved-in-genetically-preserving-and-cloning-my-pet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genetic Preservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[genetic preservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veterinarian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What Role Do Vets Play in Pet Genetic Preservation and Cloning? Ok, you’ve done the hard part. You’ve thought of your future after your pet passes. Preserving your pet’s genes opens a new window for extending your relationship with your beloved pet.  Now what? What’s the next step? Let’s walk through the detailed steps of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/are-veterinarians-involved-in-genetically-preserving-and-cloning-my-pet/">Are Veterinarians Involved in Genetically Preserving and Cloning My Pet?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>What Role Do Vets Play in Pet Genetic Preservation and Cloning?</h2>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Ok, you’ve done the hard part. You’ve thought of your future after your pet passes. Preserving your pet’s genes opens a new window for extending your relationship with your beloved pet.  Now what? What’s the next step? Let’s walk through the detailed steps of what to do next.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">1. First, check out the <a href="https://viagenpets.com/team/">ViaGen Pets</a> website. This is a good place to begin getting an idea of what preserving your pet’s genes really means and what that entails. Make sure to check out the <a href="https://viagenpets.com/faq/"><span style="color: #a61414;">FAQs</span></a>.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">2. Next, you&#8217;ll want to talk to a ViaGen Pets Representative to discuss the process of genetic preservation (GP). At this time you can also ask any questions you have about <span style="color: #000000;">cloning your pet</span>. If you don’t feel like you have further questions at this time after visiting the website, then you can skip the call and just place the order for a <a href="https://viagenpets.com/product/genetic-preservation/"><span style="color: #a61414;">Genetic Preservation Kit online.</span></a></p>
<h2>We Will Provide Your Vet With All of the Information and Instructions Needed for Biopsies</h2>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">3. Before a Genetic Preservation Kit is sent out, you&#8217;ll want to talk to your veterinarian. If your veterinarian has not worked with ViaGen Pets before, he or she can review <span style="color: #a61414;"><a style="color: #a61414;" href="https://viagenpets.com/veterinarian/">information for veterinarians</a></span> on our website and can request biopsy instructions to look over in advance. You can let your vet know that your pet will need a simple skin punch biopsy. If they have further technical questions, they can always call ViaGen Pets. If needed, you can also ask a ViaGen Pets Representative for a referral veterinarian in your area. These vets are familiar with the procedure and the purpose of it.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">4. You will need to set up a<strong> biopsy appointment</strong> with your veterinarian prior to the Genetic Preservation Kit being sent out. The Kit will have a two week lifespan so it’s best to have it sent a couple days before the appointment. If you have a routine appointment already scheduled, like teeth cleaning, it might be preferable to do this biopsy collection at the same time.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">5. ViaGen Pets’ genetic preservation procedure requires two skin tissue biopsy samples, but recommends four. So the maximum tissue collection your veterinarian will perform is 4 tissue biopsy samples,  4 mm in size each. The tissue biopsy collection is a very simple and straightforward procedure that does not harm your pet. Your veterinarian should already be familiar with the biopsy instructions as they routinely perform biopsies for other purposes at their clinic. You should speak with your veterinarian about the cost of biopsy collection as it is separate from ViaGen Pets’ cost for genetic preservation.</p>
<h2>Your Cloned Pet Should Have Normal Veterinary Care</h2>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Once you are ready to clone your pet, ViaGen Pets will already have frozen millions of your pet’s cells. The <a href="https://viagenpets.com/pet-cloning-2/">cloning procedure</a> will be done by ViaGen Pets and will not involve your local veterinarian. Once your cloned twin is born, he or she will be examined and monitored by ViaGen Pets&#8217; own veterinarians.  Once it is time to take your new baby home, you should then schedule a follow up exam with your veterinarian to have any normal additional vaccinations administered and/or routine heartworm and flea/tick prevention.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">And as with any other pet, you&#8217;ll want to continue to visit your veterinarian for <span style="color: #a61414;"><a style="color: #a61414;" href="https://www.avma.org/public/PetCare/Pages/wellness-exams.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">routine veterinary care</a></span>.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Posted by Sanaz.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/are-veterinarians-involved-in-genetically-preserving-and-cloning-my-pet/">Are Veterinarians Involved in Genetically Preserving and Cloning My Pet?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
