<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized Archives | Viagen Pets</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.viagenpets.com/category/uncategorized/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/category/uncategorized/</link>
	<description>Love the lasts forever</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 16:56:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Cowboys in Vegas!</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/cowboys-in-vegas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 16:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=4767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We are quickly approaching the greatest 10 days of the “Cowboy Lifestyle.” The National Finals Rodeo will take place from December 6th through the 15th at the Thomas &#38; Mack Center in Las Vegas, Nevada. Very exciting for ViaGen Pets &#38; Equine, cloning has recently become important to improving bull and bronc herds often used [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/cowboys-in-vegas/">Cowboys in Vegas!</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are quickly approaching the greatest 10 days of the “Cowboy Lifestyle.” The National Finals Rodeo will take place from December 6<sup>th</sup> through the 15<sup>th</sup> at the Thomas &amp; Mack Center in Las Vegas, Nevada.</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4768" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/v-300x270.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="270" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/v-300x270.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/v-1024x922.jpg 1024w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/v-768x692.jpg 768w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/v.jpg 1167w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Very exciting for ViaGen Pets &amp; Equine, cloning has recently become important to improving bull and bronc herds often used at the NFR. Though no bucking horses have performed in Vegas yet, clones are being used for breeding in many outstanding herds, and we will see offspring of these in Las Vegas soon. When we do, it won’t be the first time that a clone has been used to showcase the talents of these cowboys at the National Finals Rodeo. The cloned bucking bulls of Panhandle Slim have come leaping out of those yellow chutes already! Also, there are a few barrel horses that left their mark on the toughest rodeo in the world, and their owners decided to continue their legacy. 10X World Champion Barrel Racer, Charmayne James, cloned her great horse, Scamper and World Champion Barrel Racer, Mary Walker, cloned her superstar athlete, Perculatin aka “Latte.”…and this is only to name a few.</p>
<p>The NFR performances begin at 6:45pm in the evening, but don’t think that will leave you sitting around all morning and afternoon twiddling your thumbs! Vendors come to Vegas and set up so many shops, you will have trouble getting through them all. Christmas shopping is a piece of cake with everything for sale from cowboy hats, to rustic furniture, all the way to Range Rovers. This shopping spree has been named “Cowboy Christmas,” and many people wait all year just for the exciting time when this many vendors come together.</p>
<p>Also taking place during the daytime while in Las Vegas for the National Finals Rodeo is the Jr. NFR. This is a relatively new event that allows youth, 18 &amp; under, to compete in a very similar fashion to how they watch their heroes compete each night at the Thomas &amp; Mack Center. This year, the Jr. NFR will take place at the Las Vegas Convention Center which is also home for one of the biggest Cowboy Christmas locations. This year, I will be competing at the Jr. NFR in the breakaway roping aboard a great mare that is the offspring of a clone! If you decide to venture off the strip, in the old downtown of Las Vegas, there will be plenty more action for you to catch up on. Going on at the Plaza Hotel &amp; Casino, is the Rope for the Crown. This is a Women’s Breakaway Roping that will host only the best ropers from all over the country who have worked all year to qualify for this event. Also at the Plaza, Chris Neal’s Vegas Stars will showcase junior ropers who felt that their talents were good enough to gamble with in Vegas. Like I said, there’s action everywhere!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4769" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/v2-300x196.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="196" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/v2-300x196.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/v2-768x502.jpg 768w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/v2.jpg 992w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Another great event going on at this time is the World Series of Team Roping. This is located at the South Point Hotel &amp; Casino. At this great roping, winners can take home as much as $200,000! It is exciting to watch people giving it their all at a sport they love for a shot at such a big chunk of change! The South Point also has hundreds of vendors set up at the roping. Truthfully, there is shopping to do everywhere you go…</p>
<p>If you get to make the trip to Vegas for this “Superbowl of Rodeo,” then I hope I prepared you for some of the excitement to come and the events that can fill your days. For those of you who are regular to the NFR experience, I can feel your anxiety for departure day from here. Now for those of you, who have never been to this magnificent 10 day event, add it to you bucket list. Most importantly, if you’re a rookie to the trip, go out of habit, or are jotting it down on your to-do list… contact ViaGen Pets &amp; Equine to learn more about cloning your dog, cat, or horse. We are happy to answer any questions you may have! We will also be out in Las Vegas for the entire 10 days, so if you would like to meet up, we are available for that as well!</p>
<p>By: Lexie Russell</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/cowboys-in-vegas/">Cowboys in Vegas!</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Pet Diabetes Month</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/national-pet-diabetes-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 21:16:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=4702</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>1 out of every 100 dogs that reaches the age of 12 will develop diabetes.  In cats it’s estimated that 1 in 250 cats will develop diabetes. What is diabetes? Diabetes is an illness caused when the body cannot use sugar normally (sugar diabetes).  This is the more common type called diabetes mellitus.  Diabetes insipidus [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/national-pet-diabetes-month/">National Pet Diabetes Month</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>1 out of every 100 dogs that reaches the age of 12 will develop diabetes.  In cats it’s estimated that 1 in 250 cats will develop diabetes.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4703" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/x-300x170.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="170" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/x-300x170.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/x.jpg 688w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><strong>What is diabetes?</strong></p>
<p>Diabetes is an illness caused when the body cannot use sugar normally (sugar diabetes).  This is the more common type called diabetes mellitus.  Diabetes insipidus (water diabetes) is less common with a completely different cause and different treatment.   Since most pets that have diabetes mellitus, we will further discuss this type.</p>
<p><strong>Key facts about diabetes in dogs and cats</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Diabetes in pets may cause death if left untreated.</li>
<li>Diet is a significant factor in causing and in treating diabetes.</li>
<li>How <a href="https://www.1800petmeds.com/Diabetes-cat80.html">insulin</a> is given affects how quickly and how long it works.</li>
<li>Some pets need insulin for a period, then recover and no longer need it.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>How common is it?</strong></p>
<p>Overweight pets have a higher risk of developing diabetes.</p>
<p>In dogs, diabetes mellitus is common in middle-aged to older animals, especially in females.  Certain breeds of dogs also experience above-average rates of diabetes like miniature poodles, dachshunds, Australian terriers, Beagles, Samoyeds, and Burmese.  In cats, male cats are more likely to develop diabetes.</p>
<p>If it’s seen in younger animals, it can be a sign that your cat or dog is genetically predisposed to diabetes—this can mean that related animals may also be predisposed.</p>
<p><strong>Signs of diabetes in pets</strong></p>
<p>The earlier it is diagnosed, the better chance your pet may have for a longer and healthier life.  Here are some signs to watch out for:</p>
<ul>
<li>Excessive water drinking and increased urination</li>
<li>Weight loss, even though there may be an increased appetite</li>
<li>Decreased appetite</li>
<li>Cloudy eyes (especially in dogs)</li>
<li>Chronic or recurring infections (including skin infections and urinary infections)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Treatment for diabetes?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Diet</strong></li>
<li><strong>Exercise</strong></li>
<li><strong>Insulin Injections</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4704" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/y-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/y-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/y.jpg 462w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />    <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4705" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/z.jpg" alt="" width="147" height="178" />    <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4706" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/zz-300x171.png" alt="" width="300" height="171" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/zz-300x171.png 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/zz.png 700w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><strong>What is Insulin?</strong></p>
<p>Insulin is a hormone produced by certain cells in the pancreas that keeps your pet&#8217;s glucose concentration at a normal level while delivering glucose (energy) to the body&#8217;s cells.</p>
<p>Because diabetes is caused by a lack or shortage of insulin, your pet may need management with insulin.</p>
<p>Diabetes can usually be controlled by simply learning to give your pet daily insulin injections to control blood glucose level.   Your veterinarian will help you find your pet’s correct dose. This process may take a few weeks, but the end result is very manageable. Once you have the correct insulin dose, it is extremely important that you administer your pet&#8217;s therapy <strong>at approximately the same time every day.</strong></p>
<p>In general, diabetes cannot be cured. However, the good news is that with proper monitoring, treatment, and diet and exercise, diabetic pets can lead a happy, healthy life.</p>
<p>If you are interested in preserving your pet’s genetics, please contact ViaGen Pets at 1-888-876-6104 or at <a href="http://www.ViaGenPets.com">www.ViaGenPets.com</a> for more information about Genetic Preservation.</p>
<p>By: Sanaz</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/national-pet-diabetes-month/">National Pet Diabetes Month</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Pet Cancer Awareness Month</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/national-pet-cancer-awareness-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 21:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=4629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that November is National Pet Cancer Awareness Month? Cancer is the leading cause of death for dogs in the United States. One in four dogs and one in five cats are likely to get cancer. With rates that staggering let’s get serious here. Warning Signs &#38; Symptoms Changes in eating habits Fluctuations [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/national-pet-cancer-awareness-month/">National Pet Cancer Awareness Month</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that November is National Pet Cancer Awareness Month? Cancer is the leading cause of death for dogs in the United States. One in four dogs and one in five cats are likely to get cancer. With rates that staggering let’s get serious here.</p>
<div id="attachment_4630" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-4630" class="wp-image-4630 size-medium" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/coco-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/coco-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/coco-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/coco-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/coco-768x768.jpg 768w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/coco-100x100.jpg 100w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/coco-71x71.jpg 71w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/coco.jpg 1280w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-4630" class="wp-caption-text">Coco &#8211; 14 yr old Chocolate Lab with Squamous Cell Carcinoma</p></div>
<p>Warning Signs &amp; Symptoms</p>
<ul>
<li>Changes in eating habits</li>
<li>Fluctuations in weight</li>
<li>Abnormal body order</li>
<li>Lethargic</li>
<li>Hard time chewing and swallowing food</li>
<li>Bleeding</li>
<li>Increase in body lumps</li>
</ul>
<p>Most Common Pet Cancers</p>
<ul>
<li>Skin Cancer – raised mass or lesion on the skin</li>
<li>Osteosarcoma – bone cancer</li>
<li>Mammary Gland Tumors – mostly found in unspayed females</li>
<li>Lymphosarcoma – occurs in white blood cells and affects the immune system</li>
<li>Soft Tissue Sarcomas – found in lymph nodes, fat, blood vessels, nervous tissue, muscle and joints</li>
</ul>
<p>Common Treatment Options</p>
<ul>
<li>Chemotherapy</li>
<li>Radiation</li>
<li>Surgery</li>
<li>Immunotherapy</li>
<li>Antibody Therapy</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are lucky enough to have a pet at home, it is very important to ensure your pet has regular visits with their veterinarian.  These annuals visits allow for the veterinarian to exam your pet firsthand and be on top of anything that could potentially develop into a serious or more serious condition.  Annual blood-work and fecal testing are so important for the overall heath and well being of your pet.</p>
<p>Our pets are only with us for a short lifetime. Make that time the most enjoyable, healthy experience for both you and your pet.</p>
<p>To learn more about ViaGen Pets &amp; Equine and the services we provided please call us at 888-876-6104.</p>
<p>By: Lauren</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/national-pet-cancer-awareness-month/">National Pet Cancer Awareness Month</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pets &#038; Halloween</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/pets-halloween/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 12:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=4612</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>During Halloween many humans wear costumes, and some also try to include their pet in on the fun. While there are many cute costumes available, pet owners should be aware of their pet’s disposition when trying to dress them. One thing that should not be scary during Halloween is getting your pet dressed up. While [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/pets-halloween/">Pets &#038; Halloween</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-4613 size-medium" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/iStock-1023732830-300x162.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="162" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/iStock-1023732830-300x162.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/iStock-1023732830-1024x552.jpg 1024w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/iStock-1023732830-768x414.jpg 768w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/iStock-1023732830.jpg 1395w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>During Halloween many humans wear costumes, and some also try to include their pet in on the fun. While there are many cute costumes available, pet owners should be aware of their pet’s disposition when trying to dress them.</p>
<p>One thing that should not be scary during Halloween is getting your pet dressed up. While the costumes look totally adorable, we need to be mindful of how your pet feels about wearing clothing. There are a few training methods to teach your dog to get dressed, but my favorite is making everything into a circle so they can choose to put their head through it. Start with a circle ring shaped object and hold it in the air near your pet and place your other hand (full of treats) on the opposite side. Lure your pet through the hoop and rewards them for coming close or even stick their nose through. Eventually your pet will stick their entire head through, and this is really the primary goal. Once you can get the ring over their head without hesitation move on to something simple like a hat with a chin strap and hold the item open in a circle. Your pet will make the connection and stick their head through to get a treat on the other side. Repeat this process, and graduate how long the items stays on your pet- start with 1 second, then 2 seconds, then 5 seconds, etc. They will become soon comfortable with having that object on them. Remember to always use positive reinforcement! This idea translates into t-shirts, jackets, sweaters, and even Halloween costumes. Use the “head hole” of the clothing as a circle to invite your pet to get dressed. The dog is choosing to get dressed and this overall makes it less stressful on them. Plan your pet’s costume early and give them ample time to get acclimated to it before taking them out to show it off. Check out <a href="http://www.vetstreet.com/our-pet-experts/teach-your-dog-to-wear-clothes">this</a> article for other training suggestions.</p>
<p>Halloween is also about treats- not just tricks! Don’t forget to include your pet in on the festive foods. Here are a few of my pet’s favorites this season:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Fruitables-Skinny-Treats-Pumpkin-Flavor/dp/B00702DYSQ/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1540957828&amp;sr=8-3&amp;keywords=dog+pumpkin+berry+treats">Fruitables Skinny Minis Dog Treats- Pumpkin and Berry</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Fromm-Four-Star-Cranberry-Low-Fat-6-Ounce/dp/B000WFRNU8/ref=sr_1_7?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1540957941&amp;sr=8-7&amp;keywords=dog+cranberry+treats+fromm">Fromm Four-Star Cranberry Liver Low-Fat Dog Treats</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Members-Mark-Treats-Peanut-Flavored/dp/B07JLS5C94/ref=sr_1_1_a_it?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1540958106&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=dog+pumpkin+members+mark">Member&#8217;s Mark Grain Free Dog Treats, Peanut Butter Flavored</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Here are some great costume ideas:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00CJQ4MLG/ref=s9_acsd_simh_hd_bw_b3FM88B_c_x_w?pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;pf_rd_s=merchandised-search-3&amp;pf_rd_r=13P9V14M0NEXGJY27NTV&amp;pf_rd_r=13P9V14M0NEXGJY27NTV&amp;pf_rd_t=101&amp;pf_rd_p=f8e1ec98-9ed7-5097-88e2-4936c81e4b51&amp;pf_rd_p=f8e1ec98-9ed7-5097-88e2-4936c81e4b51&amp;pf_rd_i=2975318011">Fifties Girl</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00UXVNIBE/ref=s9_acsd_top_hd_bw_b3FM88B_c_x_w?pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;pf_rd_s=merchandised-search-4&amp;pf_rd_r=13P9V14M0NEXGJY27NTV&amp;pf_rd_r=13P9V14M0NEXGJY27NTV&amp;pf_rd_t=101&amp;pf_rd_p=dbfe16bd-c895-5e83-ad34-34e58be5b3a8&amp;pf_rd_p=dbfe16bd-c895-5e83-ad34-34e58be5b3a8&amp;pf_rd_i=2975318011">Lion Mane</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01ENZV6YG/ref=s9_acsd_top_hd_bw_b3FM88B_c_x_w?pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;pf_rd_s=merchandised-search-4&amp;pf_rd_r=13P9V14M0NEXGJY27NTV&amp;pf_rd_r=13P9V14M0NEXGJY27NTV&amp;pf_rd_t=101&amp;pf_rd_p=dbfe16bd-c895-5e83-ad34-34e58be5b3a8&amp;pf_rd_p=dbfe16bd-c895-5e83-ad34-34e58be5b3a8&amp;pf_rd_i=2975318011">UPS Pal</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B010DXW6IM/ref=s9_acsd_top_hd_bw_b3FM88B_c_x_w?pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;pf_rd_s=merchandised-search-4&amp;pf_rd_r=13P9V14M0NEXGJY27NTV&amp;pf_rd_r=13P9V14M0NEXGJY27NTV&amp;pf_rd_t=101&amp;pf_rd_p=dbfe16bd-c895-5e83-ad34-34e58be5b3a8&amp;pf_rd_p=dbfe16bd-c895-5e83-ad34-34e58be5b3a8&amp;pf_rd_i=2975318011">Pirate</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B071DS7FFK/ref=s9_acsd_zgift_hd_bw_b3FM88B_c_x_w?pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;pf_rd_s=merchandised-search-12&amp;pf_rd_r=13P9V14M0NEXGJY27NTV&amp;pf_rd_r=13P9V14M0NEXGJY27NTV&amp;pf_rd_t=101&amp;pf_rd_p=341f68d3-566e-54ab-9ea1-d03b238fadc5&amp;pf_rd_p=341f68d3-566e-54ab-9ea1-d03b238fadc5&amp;pf_rd_i=2975318011">Cowboy Rider</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/California-Costumes-Collections-PET20149-Costume/dp/B01E0DXKGS/ref=sr_1_5?s=pet-supplies&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1540957468&amp;sr=1-5&amp;keywords=dog+spider+halloween+costumes">Spider</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Pandaloon-Panda-Puppy-Costume-Height/dp/B075R3YDSF/ref=sr_1_4?s=pet-supplies&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1540957281&amp;sr=1-4&amp;keywords=panda">Panda</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/hannahloewentheil/18-dogs-who-completely-won-halloween?utm_term=.jv7wBAgyb#.kc8V9oDw7">Buzzfeed Article</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Have fun with your pet this Halloween! Keep in mind there are a lot of new sounds, smells, spooky items, and funny looking people- so be patient and understanding with your pet. Halloween can be overwhelming for our animals, so make sure your pet is in a safe and comforting controlled environment. Halloween is meant to scare humans, not our furry friends.</p>
<p>Please safely store any candy items- be cautious of what your dog/cat could ingest! Check out this <a href="https://viagenpets.com/national-animal-safety-and-protection/">ViaGen blog</a> about animal safety and protection.</p>
<p>By: Emily</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/pets-halloween/">Pets &#038; Halloween</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fun Dog Facts</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/fun-dog-facts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 19:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=4599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Newfoundland breed has a water resistant coat and webbed feet. This dog was originally bred to help haul nets for fishermen and rescuing people at risk of drowning. Much like a person’s fingerprint, a dog’s nose print is unique. Human blood pressure goes down when petting a dog. And so does the dog’s. When dogs kick [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/fun-dog-facts/">Fun Dog Facts</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4600" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/12-1-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/12-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/12-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/12-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/12-1.jpg 1431w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<ol>
<li>The <a href="https://www.petfinder.com/dog-breeds/Newfoundland">Newfoundland breed </a>has a water resistant coat and webbed feet. This dog was originally bred to help haul nets for fishermen and rescuing people at risk of drowning.</li>
<li>Much like a person’s fingerprint, a dog’s nose print is unique.</li>
<li>Human blood pressure goes down when petting a dog. And so does the dog’s.</li>
<li>When dogs kick after going to the bathroom, they are using the scent glands on their paws to further mark their territory.<br />
<em>Source: </em><em><a href="http://www.healthypet.com/KidsKlub/FunFactsArticle.aspx?title=Dogs_Ever_Wonder">Healthy Pet</a></em></li>
<li>All dogs can be traced back 40 million years ago to a weasel-like animal called the Miacis which dwelled in trees and dens. The Miacis later evolved into the Tomarctus, a direct forbear of the genus Canis, which includes the wolf and jackal as well as the dog.</li>
<li>A group of pugs is called a &#8220;grumble.&#8221;</li>
<li>While cats have around only 473 taste buds, dogs have about 1,700 taste buds. Humans have approximately 9,000.</li>
<li>Puppies have 28 teeth and normal adult dogs have 42. They’re also blind and deaf at birth.<br />
<em>Source: </em><em><a href="http://vetmedicine.about.com/cs/diseasesall/a/dentalcare.htm">com</a></em></li>
<li>Some dogs can smell dead bodies under water, where termites are hiding, and natural gas buried under 40 feet of dirt. They can even detect cancer that is too small to be detected by a doctor and can find lung cancer by sniffing a person’s breath.</li>
<li>Dogs can smell about 1,000-10,000 times better than humans. While humans have 5 million smell-detecting cells, dogs have more than 220 million. The part of the brain that interprets smell is also four times larger in dogs than in humans.</li>
<li>Dogs’ noses secrete a thin layer of mucous that helps them absorb scent. They then lick their noses to sample the scent through their mouth.<br />
<em>Source: <a href="http://www.vetstreet.com/our-pet-experts/why-does-my-dog-have-a-wet-nose">Vetstreet</a></em></li>
<li>Dogs’ eyes contain a special membrane, called the tapetum lucidum, which allows them to see in the dark.<br />
<em>Source: </em><em><a href="http://www.healthypet.com/KidsKlub/FunFactsArticle.aspx?title=Dogs_Ever_Wonder">Healthy Pet</a></em></li>
<li>The average dog can run about 19 mph. Greyhounds are the fastest dogs on Earth and can run at speeds of 45 mph.</li>
<li>Zorba, an English mastiff, is the biggest dog ever recorded. He weighed 343 pounds and measured 8’ 3&#8243; from his nose to his tail.</li>
<li>It costs approximately $10,000 to train a federally certified search and rescued</li>
</ol>
<p>Another super cool fun fact is for only $1,600 you can preserve the DNA of your furry friend forever with ViaGen Pets.  Simply call us at 888-876-6104 to learn more!</p>
<p>By: Dennis</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/fun-dog-facts/">Fun Dog Facts</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Veterinary Technicians; the Unsung Heroes of the Veterinary Clinic</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/veterinary-technicians-the-unsung-heroes-of-the-veterinary-clinic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 14:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=4571</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; Veterinary Technicians are an integral part of the veterinary hospital team. Their role extends well beyond what is taught in school or is evident on paper, and they are some of the most incredibly compassionate, caring, selfless and kind individuals on the planet. The expertise, guidance and assistance of a top notch veterinary technician [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/veterinary-technicians-the-unsung-heroes-of-the-veterinary-clinic/">Veterinary Technicians; the Unsung Heroes of the Veterinary Clinic</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4573" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/National-Vet-Tech-Week-1-300x251.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="251" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/National-Vet-Tech-Week-1-300x251.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/National-Vet-Tech-Week-1-768x644.jpg 768w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/National-Vet-Tech-Week-1.jpg 940w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Veterinary Technicians are an integral part of the veterinary hospital team. Their role extends well beyond what is taught in school or is evident on paper, and they are some of the most incredibly compassionate, caring, selfless and kind individuals on the planet. The expertise, guidance and assistance of a top notch veterinary technician is truly invaluable. Veterinary technicians make up an enormous part of the framework of a veterinary clinic; they offer continual support and guidance to the client service representatives that answer the phones and serve as the front line at the clinic. They are constant advocates for our beloved four-legged patients that don’t have their own voices. A good veterinary technician is able to pick up on some of the most minute changes in a patient to ensure that every effort is made to improve the animal’s health and enhance their veterinary experience. Veterinary technicians in many hospitals are responsible for spear-heading the ‘Fear Free’ movement that has made great strides since its inception in 2016 towards improving patient experiences at the veterinary clinic by reducing fear. Additionally, the support that veterinary technicians provide to the veterinarians that they work closely with is entirely indescribable; vet techs truly keep veterinarians on track in a million different ways.</p>
<p>At my first job as a veterinarian fresh out of veterinary school, I was lucky enough to be surrounded by a group of extremely talented, dedicated, and knowledgeable veterinary technicians. In reflecting back on that first year, I am positive that the vet techs that supported and guided me through my first emergency cases, my first surgeries and, well, just about everything about my first months as a veterinarian served to mold and shape me into the capable veterinarian that I am today. Of course, my wonderful veterinarian mentors taught me many clinical lessons, but I’ll never forget just how much knowledge I gained from working closely with all of the incredible veterinary technicians that I’ve been lucky enough to cross paths with during my veterinary career.</p>
<p>This week, October 14-20, 2018, is National Veterinary Technician Appreciation Week. This is a reminder for all of us to stop and say, “Thank you” to the amazing veterinary technicians that we know and love and that are all too often underappreciated. Many of us have been touched by the compassion of a veterinary technician, and many of our furry friends are living a better life because of the care offered by a veterinary technician, so please spend some time this week thanking these wonderful individuals. Write a quick card addressed to your favorite veterinary technician or a card addressed to all of the vet techs at the veterinary hospital where you take your pets. It’s no joke that vet clinics love food so drop off a plate of your favorite cookies, candies, donuts or even a veggie tray for the veterinary technicians at your clinic. You could even just make a quick, simple phone call to the vet clinic, ask to speak to your favorite vet tech and simply say thanks for everything that he or she has done for you and your pet. There are so many ways to express gratitude, feel free to get creative, but whatever you do, don’t forget to say thanks! A simple thank you will mean more than you’ll ever know to these hardworking, dedicated individuals. I know that I would not be half the veterinarian that I am today if the incredible technicians that I’ve had the pleasure to work with (past, present and future), didn’t do such a great job making me look good!</p>
<p>Don’t forget to read more about ViaGen Pets and our feline, canine and equine cloning and genetic preservation services at <a href="http://www.ViaGenPets.com">www.ViaGenPets.com</a>!</p>
<p>By: Kerry Ryan, DVM</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/veterinary-technicians-the-unsung-heroes-of-the-veterinary-clinic/">Veterinary Technicians; the Unsung Heroes of the Veterinary Clinic</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Animal Safety and Protection</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/national-animal-safety-and-protection/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 14:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=4557</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In addition to the many wonderful things that Fall brings such as colorful leaves, the first feelings of the cool Fall breeze and pumpkin spice everything; October is also National Animal Safety and Protection Month. This month was dedicated to creating awareness of safety and protection for domestic as well as wild animals as a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/national-animal-safety-and-protection/">National Animal Safety and Protection</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In addition to the many wonderful things that Fall brings such as colorful leaves, the first feelings of the cool Fall breeze and pumpkin spice everything; October is also National Animal Safety and Protection Month. This month was dedicated to creating awareness of safety and protection for domestic as well as wild animals as a reminder that we can have an effect on everything in our environment and we are the stewards of the animals on this earth with us. During this month you will see many animal shelters, pet stores and veterinarians promoting safety awareness for animals. This is a good time to ask about the many ways you can protect your pets.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4559" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/2.jpg" alt="" width="180" height="150" /></p>
<p>Most people wouldn’t think of pet proofing their home much in the same way as baby proofing. There are many toxic and dangerous things that a pet can get into, especially the really curious ones! <a href="https://www.petpoisonhelpline.com/poisons/">Please click here for an extensive list.</a> Always keep dangerous chemicals locked away where any pets can’t get to them. Also be sure when no one is home your pet is safe and to look around your home for anything they can get into while you are out. Funny enough they know when you are not looking! Even though we have gotten through the dog days of summer and being careful not to leave pets in the car during summer heat; the safety of your pets changes with each season including temperature, new pests and insects to be aware of and new items coming in the home due to seasonal needs.</p>
<p>Another often unexpected element is insuring that the fencing around your yard is secured so that your pet cannot get out or other animals cannot get in. It is surprising how perfectly sturdy looking fences can succumb to an excitable, barking dog that is doing everything he/she can to protect and scare away intruders or squirrels from his territory. Another item that is wonderful to have is the fire sticker below to indicate to emergency responders that there are pets in your home so they will immediately know. These can be ordered online.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4558" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/1-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/1.jpg 605w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Also as travel season is increasing due to holidays, it is a good time to ensure your travels with your pets are safe for them. A safe and secure carrier is key when traveling with pets in a car or by air. Be sure you have provided with them fresh water, especially on a long trip to avoid dehydration which then can cause your pet to a series of very serious symptoms that could have been avoided. There are so many great travel carriers available online to meet any need and style.</p>
<p>So take a moment this month and check if there is anything you can do to insure your pet’s safety and perhaps even the safety of any other animals you may have contact with. We can all do our part to avoid unnecessary and preventable harm to our pets and animals we love. With so many resources at our fingertips, it is easier than ever to get the help and advice needed for any scenario.</p>
<p>Call us to learn how we can help protect your pet with our Genetic Preservation service at 888-876-6104.</p>
<p>By: Rana</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/national-animal-safety-and-protection/">National Animal Safety and Protection</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Walk Your Dog Week</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/national-walk-your-dog-week/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 18:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=4501</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Walking your dog is a very important part of your and your furry friend’s life. National Walk your dog week was founded by Colleen Paige to bring attention to the problem of behavior issues and obesity in the canine population. If you walk your dog just 30 minutes a day you will meet national recommendations [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/national-walk-your-dog-week/">National Walk Your Dog Week</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4502" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/12-300x176.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="176" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/12-300x176.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/12-1024x602.jpg 1024w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/12-768x451.jpg 768w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/12.jpg 1431w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Walking your dog is a very important part of your and your furry friend’s life. National Walk your dog week was founded by Colleen Paige to bring attention to the problem of behavior issues and obesity in the canine population. If you walk your dog just 30 minutes a day you will meet national recommendations for heart health, says Paige. Walking is not just a part of physical health for your pooch but mental health as well. So grab that leash and those dog bags and get out there!</p>
<p>There are a lot of different types of collars and harnesses to choose from, which can make the task seem very daunting. Once you know what kind of walker your pup is the decision becomes a bit easier. For the properly trained loose leash walker you should be fine with a typical standard flat collar. If you have a shorter nosed dog, like a Frenchie or a Boston, you may want to go with a back clip harness. This can help avoid exacerbating the breathing problems these dogs tend to have when going on longer walks. If your pup likes to pull a little bit and gets a little too excited when she sees a squirrel, a front clip harness may be for you. This helps prevent minor pulling and allows you to steer the dog a little more easily. If you want to speed along the leash training process you may be interested in a head halter, similar to the <a href="https://www.chewy.com/petsafe-gentle-leader-chic-dog/dp/148619">Gentle Leader</a> or SnootLoop. These help your dog focus more on you when walking instead of sniffing their surroundings. Dogs learn more quickly when their attention is on you instead of when their nose is to the ground.</p>
<p>Also make sure that you and your pup have some sort of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ghost-Tags-Safety-Reflector-Visible/dp/B076X9N5NJ/ref=sr_1_7?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1538418322&amp;sr=8-7&amp;keywords=reflectors+dog">reflective device</a> on so any passersby can easily spot them and you when the light starts to fade.</p>
<p>Here are some links to help make sure you’re getting the most out of that walk and that everyone involved is being safe and having fun:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cesarsway.com/dog-training/walking/6-tips-for-mastering-the-dog-walk">Cesar Millan</a> has some good tips on how to make the most of your walk including where to position yourself and the kind of leash to use.</p>
<p><a href="https://healthypets.mercola.com/sites/healthypets/archive/2011/05/19/walking-your-dog-how-to-do-it-well-and-why-its-so-important.aspx">Healthy Pets</a> also has some pointers on proper technique and how important it is to your dog’s health to walk and get exercise regularly. They also instruct when it is proper to take your puppy out for a walk and some basic instructions on teaching your pup to walk on a leash.</p>
<p>And the <a href="https://www.akc.org/expert-advice/training/teach-puppy-walk-leash/">American Kennel Club</a> has a good page on how to teach the young pups to walk on a leash properly and how to trouble shoot those problem walkers.</p>
<p>Most of all enjoy the exercise for you and your pup!</p>
<p>ViaGen Pets is the worldwide leader in the cloning the animals we love! To learn more call us at 888-876-6104.</p>
<p>By: Dennis</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/national-walk-your-dog-week/">National Walk Your Dog Week</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fun Cat Facts</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/fun-cat-facts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 16:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=4485</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Our furry little feline friends are sometimes a mystery, however here are some facts we do know about them! While us humans have 206 bones, cats on average have 244. It ranges between 230-250 depending on how long a cat&#8217;s tail is and how many toes the cat has. Adult cats have 30 teeth, while [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/fun-cat-facts/">Fun Cat Facts</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4486" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/WinstonIsabella-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/WinstonIsabella-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/WinstonIsabella-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/WinstonIsabella-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/WinstonIsabella-768x768.jpg 768w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/WinstonIsabella-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/WinstonIsabella.jpg 2048w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/WinstonIsabella-100x100.jpg 100w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/WinstonIsabella-71x71.jpg 71w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Our furry little feline friends are sometimes a mystery, however here are some facts we do know about them!</p>
<ul>
<li>While us humans have 206 bones, cats on average have 244. It ranges between 230-250 depending on how long a cat&#8217;s tail is and how many toes the cat has.</li>
<li>Adult cats have 30 teeth, while kittens have 26</li>
<li>A house cat is genetically 95.6% tiger.</li>
<li>Cats can run around 48 kph (30 mph), but only over short distances. A house cat could beat superstar runner Usain Bolt in the 200 meter dash.</li>
<li>Cats can jump 5 times their height</li>
<li>An adult cat’s brain is approximately 5 cm (2 inches) long and weighs 30g and has nearly twice the amount of neurons in their cerebral cortex as dogs.</li>
<li>Males are more likely to be left pawed, while females and more likely to be right pawed- some are ambidextrous.</li>
<li>A cat’s tongue contains a number of backward facing hooks known as filiform papillae, these rough tongues can lick bones clean of any bits of meat.</li>
<li>Cats have an extra organ that allows them to taste scents in the air</li>
<li>Each cat’s nose is unique, much like human fingerprints.</li>
<li>Neutered males live 62% longer than unneutered cats, and spayed females live 39% longer than unspayed females</li>
<li>Between 2002 and 2012 the average lifespan of a cat increased by a year</li>
<li>Cat whiskers are the same width as their body</li>
<li>Cats walk like camels and giraffes, both right feet then both left feet.</li>
<li>Cats sleep 12-16 hours per day, and spend 1/3 of their awake hours grooming</li>
<li>Cats can dream</li>
<li>Grooming stimulates blood flow to the skin, regulates body temperature, and helps them relax.</li>
<li>Cats mark you as their territory by rubbing their faces and bodies against you, marking you with their scent</li>
<li>If your cat approaches you with a straight, almost vibrating tail, this means that he/she is extremely happy to see you</li>
<li>When your cat shows their belly, it is a sign of trust and a relaxed cat- this is not an invite for belly rub typically.</li>
<li>A cat’s rear end in your face is a gesture of friendship, while kneading means happiness. Draping their tail over another cat/dog/you means friendship also.</li>
<li>Meowing is a behavior cats developed to communicate with humans, and they can have up to 100 different vocalizations.</li>
<li>A cat&#8217;s purr vibrates at a frequency of 25 to 150 hertz, which is the same frequency at which muscles and bones repair themselves.</li>
<li>Grimalkin is the name of a female cat, especially an older one.</li>
<li>An ailurophile is a person who loves cats. The word ailuro is the ancient Greek word for cat.</li>
<li>There are about 88 million pet cats in the United States, which makes them the most popular pet in the country.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you want to safeguard your eternal bond with your cat, check out <a href="https://viagenpets.com/product/genetic-preservation/">this</a> information on preserving his/her DNA. This gives you the option to clone when you are ready to have a piece of him/her with you again.</p>
<p>Please refer to the sources of these cat facts to see more:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cat-world.com.au/cat-facts-cat-information.html">https://www.cat-world.com.au/cat-facts-cat-information.html</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.care.com/c/stories/6045/101-amazing-cat-facts-fun-trivia-about-your-feline-friend/">https://www.care.com/c/stories/6045/101-amazing-cat-facts-fun-trivia-about-your-feline-friend/</a></p>
<p>By: Emily</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/fun-cat-facts/">Fun Cat Facts</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Service Dog Month</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/national-service-dog-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=4469</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>September is the month to celebrate and recognize our canine companions for their extraordinary services they do every day for the people they care for.  September is used to raise awareness, appreciation and support for service dogs in the US. Service dogs are trained to help their owner with a variety of disabilities, including mental, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/national-service-dog-month/">National Service Dog Month</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4470" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/a-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/a-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/a-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/a-100x100.jpg 100w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/a-71x71.jpg 71w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/a.jpg 480w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>September is the month to celebrate and recognize our canine companions for their extraordinary services they do every day for the people they care for.  September is used to raise awareness, appreciation and support for service dogs in the US.</p>
<p>Service dogs are trained to help their owner with a variety of disabilities, including mental, physical and developmental disabilities.  Dogs understand us and can read our emotions and are naturally therapeutic to be around.</p>
<p>Here are some interesting facts about service dogs:</p>
<ul>
<li>A service dog can be any size or breed.</li>
<li>Service dogs have customized training to perform specific tasks for their owner.</li>
<li>Service dogs are legally allowed everywhere where members of the public are allowed except places where it could cause a danger/stress to the environment (like certain areas of the zoo, Sterile laboratories, places of worship)</li>
<li>Service dogs are not required to wear gear or carry paperwork</li>
</ul>
<p>In addition, service dogs can be part of our heroic group of men and women who risk their lives every day for our country.  These working canines join this group of military and first responders risking their lives every day.  Many are rescue animals but there are also programs in the US that train dogs for these critical situations.</p>
<p>One group that has dedicated their lives to training working dogs for military and law enforcement is <a href="http://www.caninetactical.com/">Canine Tactical</a>.  In addition to their training program, they have been advancing their program by utilizing the <a href="https://viagenpets.com/">ViaGen Pets</a> cloning program to reproduce their elite genetic dogs for their purpose.  Canine Tactical has cloned 3 of their different canine brands.  Eudoris<strong>®</strong> below is example and some of his clones have already joined the working canine community!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4471" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/e-193x300.jpg" alt="" width="193" height="300" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/e-193x300.jpg 193w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/e.jpg 200w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 193px) 100vw, 193px" /></p>
<p>These companion animals work hard to make life better for many people every day and dedicating a month to celebrating and honoring their work seems to be the most proper action from us.  There are so many organizations out there, just search to find the best fit for you to donate to.  So join in celebrating National Service Dog Month, consider donating your time or money to a service animal training and advocacy organization.  Not only are you helping out a companion animal you are helping a person live a better life.</p>
<p>For more information about storing DNA or cloning your pet or service animal please contact ViaGen Pets at 888-876-6104.</p>
<p>By: Sanaz</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/national-service-dog-month/">National Service Dog Month</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
