<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ViaGen Pets Cloning Articles - Learn More About Cloning Your Dog Or Cat</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.viagenpets.com/category/cloning/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/category/cloning/</link>
	<description>Love the lasts forever</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 20:29:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>I Want Pet Cloning For My Sick Pet</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/pet-cloning-for-my-sick-pet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 15:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genetic Preservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pet cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pet cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pet genetic preservation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Considering Pet Cloning for A Sick Pet Pet cloning and pet genetic preservation are two options that are now available to pet owners who have sick dogs or cats and might be approaching the end of their lives.  These situations can be heartbreaking for pet parents. We cherish the time we have with them as a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/pet-cloning-for-my-sick-pet/">I Want Pet Cloning For My Sick Pet</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family: 'Calibri',sans-serif; font-size: 11pt;"><!--?xml:namespace prefix = "o" /--></span></p>
<h1>Considering Pet Cloning for A Sick Pet</h1>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-2351" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Blog-photo-09212016.jpg" alt="pet dog paw with human hand" width="600" height="305" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Blog-photo-09212016.jpg 660w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Blog-photo-09212016-300x152.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p>Pet cloning and pet genetic preservation are two options that are now available to pet owners who have sick dogs or cats and might be approaching the end of their lives.  These situations can be heartbreaking for pet parents. We cherish the time we have with them as a puppy or kitten. We then continue to form that bond and build the relationship as they grow. Unfortunately, there is a point at the end of their lives, where we must part ways. Sometimes it’s unexpected, sometimes it is following an illness, but no matter the circumstances, it is never easy to say goodbye to a member of your family.</p>
<h2>The First Step is Pet Genetic Preservation<strong>          </strong></h2>
<p>During the last moments of your pet’s life, you may have begun searching for options and discovered media coverage of pet DNA preservation and <span style="color: #8f0e0e;"><a style="color: #8f0e0e;" href="https://viagenpets.com/dog-cloning/">pet cloning</a></span>.  In the situations where your pet is at the end of its life or has already passed, time is of the essence to help ensure your pet’s genetics can be successfully preserved.</p>
<p>Call a ViaGen Pets representative at 888-876-6104 to discuss the process and the steps to submitting tissue samples for preservation. There are emergency instructions that can be found <span style="color: #8f0e0e;"><a style="color: #8f0e0e;" href="https://viagenpets.com/emergency-pets/">here</a> </span>to assist your veterinarian in the collection and shipment of the tissue samples. These instructions will be helpful if your pet passes or the samples must be procured outside of office hours.</p>
<h2>How Does The Preservation Process Work?</h2>
<p>The cloning process begins with Genetic Preservation. Our Genetic Preservation service starts with skin punch biopsy samples taken by your veterinarian. We then culture those biopsy samples to generate new cell growth. It is those cells that we cryopreserve or freeze for long term storage. A small portion of them will be used in the future for the cloning process.</p>
<p>We recommend receiving the biopsy samples within 5 days of your pet’s passing, and your pet/tissue samples need to be kept at a refrigerated temperature (approximately 4ºC). Unfortunately with the current technology, we are not able to use other samples such as blood, hair, semen, or teeth for the cloning process.</p>
<h2>Working With You Through The Cell Culture Process</h2>
<p>We know this is a difficult time for you and your family, and we are here to discuss the process with you every step of the way. After working with your veterinarian to collect and ship the biopsy samples, we will contact you once the samples have arrived at our office, and we have started the cell culture process. We encourage you to contact us for updates on the progress of the cell culture after 1-2 weeks.</p>
<p>Once the culture is complete, we will communicate the number of cells that have been cryopreserved for your pet. On average, the culture process typically takes 4 weeks to be completed. We can then work with you to determine when moving forward with cloning is right for you and your family. By having preserved your precious pet’s genetics with us, you will have that option whether it is within the year or 10 years from now. You also have the option of simply keeping your pet’s cells cryopreserved with no commitment to move forward with the cloning process until you are ready. The cells will remain viable indefinitely.</p>
<h2>Being Ready For The Option of Pet Cloning</h2>
<p>Preserving your pet’s genetics won’t eliminate the grief that comes from their loss, but it may provide comfort in knowing you are honoring the memory of your beloved pet in this manner.  This crucial first step after the loss of a pet also gives you the option to consider pet cloning.  Many of our clients choose to clone their pets at a later date, well after their pet loss.  At the moment of grief they may not have been ready to make a final decision on cloning.  In this way, it&#8217;s easy to think of genetic preservation as providing as simply a prudent step that preserves options at a time that can be very stressful.</p>
<p>If you do decide to produce a genetic twin to your pet using the cloning process, it can also bring great joy to your family as you begin to make new memories with your happy, healthy puppy or kitten. The story of your lives, and the unique bond you have with your beloved pet is “to be continued.&#8221;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/pet-cloning-for-my-sick-pet/">I Want Pet Cloning For My Sick Pet</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Much Does It Cost To Clone A Pet?</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/cost-to-clone-pet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 18:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2277</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How Much Does It Cost To Clone My Dog or Cat? Pet owners are very fortunate today.  ViaGen Pets can produce a genetic twin to your beloved cat for $50,000, or your faithful dog for $50,000. One question you may ask is &#8220;Why does it cost that much to clone a pet?&#8221; The answer is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/cost-to-clone-pet/">How Much Does It Cost To Clone A Pet?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>How Much Does It Cost To Clone My Dog or Cat?</h1>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">Pet owners are very fortunate today.  ViaGen Pets can produce a genetic twin to your beloved cat for $50,000, or your faithful dog for $50,000. One question you may ask is &#8220;Why does it cost that much to clone a pet?&#8221; The answer is fairly simple. The ViaGen Pets cloning program is an all-inclusive service that covers every aspect of the process. It is the &#8220;Cadillac&#8221; of animal care and technology development. In order to ensure the highest level of care for donors and recipients, as well as cloned kittens and puppies, we provide state of the art housing, high nutrition diets, expert veterinary care and many other features that enrich the animal’s lives to keep them happy and healthy. Furthermore, the process of cloning cats and dogs is relatively new, so the technology is constantly under improvement. Cloning requires a very unique skill set. In order to provide this service to you, the pet owner, it is imperative that we complete our team with world-wide experts who have been highly trained to provide good outcomes. These scientists require a dedicated laboratory, with very specialized equipment in order to produce the miracle that results in your cloned kitten or puppy.</span></span></p>
<h2 dir="LTR" align="LEFT"><a href="https://viagenpets.com/cat-cloning/"><span style="color: #8c1616;">Learn More About Cat Cloning</span></a></h2>
<h2><span style="color: #8c1616;"><a style="color: #8c1616;" href="https://viagenpets.com/dog-cloning/">Learn More About Dog Cloning</a></span></h2>
<p>In order to improve the cloning process in pets and to reduce the cost, ViaGen Pets is diligently researching the dog and cat reproductive cycles to gain a better understanding. We are hopeful that in the future, the cost of cloning your pet will be less than it is today. Through research and refinement of the production process in both cats and dogs, it is our expectation that the cost of cloning your pet will be reduced, without a compromise to our unparalleled animal care and the love we show to the pets in the ViaGen Pets program.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/cost-to-clone-pet/">How Much Does It Cost To Clone A Pet?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are Cloned Pets as Healthy as Other Pets?</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/cloned-pets-healthy-pets/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 14:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pet cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pet cloning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2163</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Are There Any Health Considerations When Cloning a Pet? The first question most people have when they find out they can clone their pet is, &#8220;how much?&#8221; The answer, a lot. For the people that can get past that, the next question is, &#8220;will the clone you deliver be as healthy as my original pet?&#8221;  [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/cloned-pets-healthy-pets/">Are Cloned Pets as Healthy as Other Pets?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Are There Any Health Considerations When Cloning a Pet?</h1>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-2164 aligncenter" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/pet-cloning-health-2.jpg" alt="pet cloning health" width="630" height="300" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/pet-cloning-health-2.jpg 630w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/pet-cloning-health-2-300x143.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 630px) 100vw, 630px" /></p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">The first question most people have when they find out they can clone their pet is, &#8220;how much?&#8221; The answer, a lot. For the people that can get past that, the next question is, &#8220;will the clone you deliver be as healthy as my original pet?&#8221;  And the answer to that question can be a bit more involved.</p>
<h2 dir="LTR" align="LEFT">The Cloning Aging Myth</h2>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">There are a lot of rumors and stories out there about <span style="color: #8c0d0d;"><a style="color: #8c0d0d;" href="https://viagenpets.com/cat-cloning/">cloned pets</a></span> and their health and many of them originate with the first widely known clone, Dolly the sheep. One of the most common arguments you&#8217;ll hear against cloning is that the built-in biological clock that every animal has which is believed to have a large control on aging and death, telomeres, are not re-set during the cloning process. </span></span><span style="color: #8c0d0d;"><a style="color: #8c0d0d;" href="http://www.fda.gov/AnimalVeterinary/SafetyHealth/AnimalCloning/ucm055512.htm#Myth6" target="_blank"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span lang="EN">The myth is that if a cell from a six year old animal is used to make a clone then the resulting clone will have a functioning age of six years at birth.</span></span></span></a></span><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span lang="EN"> This is one story that is told over and over about Dolly. While Dolly’s telomeres did appear to be shorter than other sheep of a similar age they were not telomeres of an old animal. Extensive health screens carried out at the time failed to identify any abnormality that would suggest premature aging. </span></span></span></p>
<h2 dir="LTR" align="LEFT">The Reality</h2>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-2165 alignleft" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/pet-cloning-health-1.jpg" alt="dolly pet cloning health" width="300" height="210" /></p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">The reality is </span></span><span style="color: #8c0d0d;"><a style="color: #8c0d0d;" href="http://www.pnas.org/content/101/21/8034.full" target="_blank"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span lang="EN">that cloning has been shown to reset telomeres</span></span></span></a></span><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span lang="EN"> during the embryo creation process and a cloned pet that is born, no matter the age of the donor cell, will have telomeres that look and act normal for a newborn animal. Studies show that telomeres are age-appropriate in all tissues of the animal and many clones alive today have lived long, healthy lives. Of course, illness happens and it is always best to make sure that you maintain a good relationship between your pet and your veterinarian.</span></span></span></p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">Dolly is said to have died from a cloning related illness and people use that as an argument to show that </span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span lang="EN">all clones are severely damaged animals that suffer and have health problems all their lives.</span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span lang="EN"> While Dolly did die a little prematurely, the cause of her death was not an extraordinary one. Dolly ended up contracting a common illness in sheep which is, unfortunately, incurable. The virus she contracted causes a disease known as sheep pulmonary adenomatosis, or SPA. It is a disease that passes quickly and easily through sheep that have close contact with each other. Because the clones were all housed together it was only a matter of time before they all succumbed to this highly contagious disease once one of the animals contracted it. Fortunately, before she died Dolly was able to have two healthy litters of lambs. Her genetics were even preserved and she has since been recreated, with four clones of Dolly living out healthy lives in England.</span></span></span></p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;">Cloning technology has come a long way in the twenty years since Dolly’s creation. While there may not be much data to look at in terms of the health of cloned cats and dogs just yet, there is no reason to think that there will be an increase in notable health problems that are not already seen and treated in other species. The few dogs that have been cloned are living normal, happy healthy lives and are even </span></span><span style="color: #8c0d0d;"><a style="color: #8c0d0d;" href="http://www.cnn.com/2011/09/30/tech/innovation/sniffer-dog-clone-incheon/" target="_blank"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span lang="EN">joining the work force!</span></span></span></a></span><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span lang="EN"> And, of course, Viagen Pets always provides our clients with a veterinarian inspected healthy puppy or kitten. </span></span></span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/cloned-pets-healthy-pets/">Are Cloned Pets as Healthy as Other Pets?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#8217;s Not Unusual&#8230;Pet Cloning and GP Questions</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/its-not-unusual-pet-cloning-and-gp-questions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 15:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genetic Preservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pet cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frequently asked questions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2045</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Frequently Asked Pet Cloning and GP Questions We hear from many pet owners every day with questions about pet genetic preservation and cloning. Nearly every conversation we have starts with the owner saying “I’ve got an unusual question for you,&#8221; which isn’t a surprising preface for the questions we hear because pet genetic preservation and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/its-not-unusual-pet-cloning-and-gp-questions/">It&#8217;s Not Unusual&#8230;Pet Cloning and GP Questions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1><strong>Frequently Asked Pet Cloning and GP Questions</strong></h1>
<p>We hear from many pet owners every day with questions about pet genetic preservation and cloning. Nearly every conversation we have starts with the owner saying “I’ve got an unusual question for you,&#8221; which isn’t a surprising preface for the questions we hear because pet genetic preservation and cloning isn’t something that is talked about daily like the weather.</p>
<p>We understand that you’re calling because you have a deep bond and relationship with your special pet that you’d love to extend forever – if possible. So while the frequently asked <span style="color: #b30e0e;"><a style="color: #b30e0e;" href="https://viagenpets.com/faq/">pet cloning and pet genetic preservation questions</a></span> section of our website is a great resource for better understanding how pet genetic preservation and cloning works, here are a few of the most frequent questions we hear.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-2046" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/faqimage-300x188.png" alt="pet cloning pet genetic preservation frequently asked questions" width="550" height="344" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/faqimage-300x188.png 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/faqimage-1024x640.png 1024w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/faqimage-768x480.png 768w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/faqimage-360x225.png 360w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/faqimage.png 1200w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>These Are NOT Unusual Questions&#8230;</h2>
<p><strong>“My pet is elderly or is in declining health, should I have the biopsy done while he or she is still living, or should I wait until they pass?”   </strong>This is completely your decision as a pet parent and also something you should consult with your veterinarian about since anesthesia (general or local) is necessary for the tissue biopsy needed from your pet. The tissue biopsy is the critical first step whether you want to simply preserve your pet’s genetics, or clone your special animal. We recommend that a tissue biopsy be done while your pet is alive and healthy. The biggest reason for this is that you will have the option to re-submit samples if the culture is not successful, which happens from time to time. If you wait to take a skin biopsy until your pet has passed away, and if the cell culture is not successful, it’s impossible to secure another skin biopsy.</p>
<p><strong>“Will my cloned pet look the same as the original, and will it have the same personality?”</strong> – Your cloned puppy or kitten will have the same coloring as the original, but the markings may not be in the same location. For example, if your dog is white and has a brown patch around his right eye, then your cloned puppy will be white but that brown patch could be located on the left eye. An exception to this is calico cats, with more information about them <span style="color: #b30e0e;"><a style="color: #b30e0e;" href="http://mentalfloss.com/article/66825/why-are-calico-cats-almost-always-female-and-always-look-different" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a></span>.</p>
<p><strong>“What happens if more than one kitten or puppy is born?”</strong> – Our contract states that if more than one cloned kitten or puppy is born in the litter you have the option of welcoming each of them into your home at no extra charge. If you are happy with just one, then we place any additional animals from the litter into a loving forever home.</p>
<p><strong>“My pet is sick with or has had (<u>ex: cancer</u>), does that mean the clone will have it as well?”. </strong>The simplified answer is this: if your pet has a genetics-rooted condition, and since a clone of your pet carries the identical genetic make-up as the original, then the cloned animal will likely carry the same condition. However, since many pet health conditions develop as a result of a combination of genetics <em>and</em> the environment, it’s difficult to be conclusive. We encourage you to consult your veterinarian to gain a deeper perspective on your pet’s specific condition.</p>
<p>“<strong>What is the cost of cloning my dog or cat?”</strong>    ViaGen Pets charges $50,000 for cat cloning and $50,000 for dogs. The cost does not differ based on the breed or size of your dog or cat. Payment for pet cloning is made in two installments; we ask for a 50% down payment at the time you sign your pet cloning contract, and collect the balance when you take delivery of your new kitten or puppy – which happens between 8 – 12 weeks after birth.  If you are undecided whether to proceed with cloning immediately, but don’t want to miss the opportunity later, that’s no problem. We recommend you do a genetic preservation now to preserve your pet’s cells. Once a genetic preservation is successful, those cells can be stored indefinitely.  So whether you decide to move on to cloning at a later date, or just want the peace of mind knowing your pet’s DNA has been preserved, genetic preservation is available for a cat or dog for $1,600.</p>
<p>We are here to answer any questions you have, and are just a phone call away!   Feel free to contact us at 888-876-6104. You can also submit an inquiry with your questions through our website and we will contact you.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/its-not-unusual-pet-cloning-and-gp-questions/">It&#8217;s Not Unusual&#8230;Pet Cloning and GP Questions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are Veterinarians Involved in Genetically Preserving and Cloning My Pet?</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/are-veterinarians-involved-in-genetically-preserving-and-cloning-my-pet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genetic Preservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[genetic preservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veterinarian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What Role Do Vets Play in Pet Genetic Preservation and Cloning? Ok, you’ve done the hard part. You’ve thought of your future after your pet passes. Preserving your pet’s genes opens a new window for extending your relationship with your beloved pet.  Now what? What’s the next step? Let’s walk through the detailed steps of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/are-veterinarians-involved-in-genetically-preserving-and-cloning-my-pet/">Are Veterinarians Involved in Genetically Preserving and Cloning My Pet?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>What Role Do Vets Play in Pet Genetic Preservation and Cloning?</h2>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Ok, you’ve done the hard part. You’ve thought of your future after your pet passes. Preserving your pet’s genes opens a new window for extending your relationship with your beloved pet.  Now what? What’s the next step? Let’s walk through the detailed steps of what to do next.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">1. First, check out the <a href="https://viagenpets.com/team/">ViaGen Pets</a> website. This is a good place to begin getting an idea of what preserving your pet’s genes really means and what that entails. Make sure to check out the <a href="https://viagenpets.com/faq/"><span style="color: #a61414;">FAQs</span></a>.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">2. Next, you&#8217;ll want to talk to a ViaGen Pets Representative to discuss the process of genetic preservation (GP). At this time you can also ask any questions you have about <span style="color: #000000;">cloning your pet</span>. If you don’t feel like you have further questions at this time after visiting the website, then you can skip the call and just place the order for a <a href="https://viagenpets.com/product/genetic-preservation/"><span style="color: #a61414;">Genetic Preservation Kit online.</span></a></p>
<h2>We Will Provide Your Vet With All of the Information and Instructions Needed for Biopsies</h2>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">3. Before a Genetic Preservation Kit is sent out, you&#8217;ll want to talk to your veterinarian. If your veterinarian has not worked with ViaGen Pets before, he or she can review <span style="color: #a61414;"><a style="color: #a61414;" href="https://viagenpets.com/veterinarian/">information for veterinarians</a></span> on our website and can request biopsy instructions to look over in advance. You can let your vet know that your pet will need a simple skin punch biopsy. If they have further technical questions, they can always call ViaGen Pets. If needed, you can also ask a ViaGen Pets Representative for a referral veterinarian in your area. These vets are familiar with the procedure and the purpose of it.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">4. You will need to set up a<strong> biopsy appointment</strong> with your veterinarian prior to the Genetic Preservation Kit being sent out. The Kit will have a two week lifespan so it’s best to have it sent a couple days before the appointment. If you have a routine appointment already scheduled, like teeth cleaning, it might be preferable to do this biopsy collection at the same time.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">5. ViaGen Pets’ genetic preservation procedure requires two skin tissue biopsy samples, but recommends four. So the maximum tissue collection your veterinarian will perform is 4 tissue biopsy samples,  4 mm in size each. The tissue biopsy collection is a very simple and straightforward procedure that does not harm your pet. Your veterinarian should already be familiar with the biopsy instructions as they routinely perform biopsies for other purposes at their clinic. You should speak with your veterinarian about the cost of biopsy collection as it is separate from ViaGen Pets’ cost for genetic preservation.</p>
<h2>Your Cloned Pet Should Have Normal Veterinary Care</h2>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Once you are ready to clone your pet, ViaGen Pets will already have frozen millions of your pet’s cells. The <a href="https://viagenpets.com/pet-cloning-2/">cloning procedure</a> will be done by ViaGen Pets and will not involve your local veterinarian. Once your cloned twin is born, he or she will be examined and monitored by ViaGen Pets&#8217; own veterinarians.  Once it is time to take your new baby home, you should then schedule a follow up exam with your veterinarian to have any normal additional vaccinations administered and/or routine heartworm and flea/tick prevention.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">And as with any other pet, you&#8217;ll want to continue to visit your veterinarian for <span style="color: #a61414;"><a style="color: #a61414;" href="https://www.avma.org/public/PetCare/Pages/wellness-exams.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">routine veterinary care</a></span>.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Posted by Sanaz.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/are-veterinarians-involved-in-genetically-preserving-and-cloning-my-pet/">Are Veterinarians Involved in Genetically Preserving and Cloning My Pet?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Pet Cloning?</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/pet-cloning-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 13:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pet cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pet cloning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=1986</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Basics of Pet Cloning There is no denying it, we love our pets. We love our pets so much that we consider them members of our family, making sacrifices in travel and living so that they can always be near us and as comfortable as possible. It is expected that Americans will spend more than [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/pet-cloning-2/">What is Pet Cloning?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 dir="LTR" align="LEFT">The Basics of Pet Cloning</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-1987 size-full" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/1.jpg" alt="pet dog " width="293" height="220" /></p>
<p>There is no denying it, we love our pets. We love our pets so much that we consider them members of our family, making sacrifices in travel and living so that they can always be near us and as comfortable as possible. It is expected that <span style="color: #a61212;"><a style="color: #a61212;" href="http://www.nbcnews.com/business/consumer/americans-will-spend-more-60-billion-their-pets-year-n390181">Americans will spend more than $60 billion on their pets this year</a></span> with most of this money being spent on safety and life enrichment. In a society where we place so much emotional and financial investment into our pets, it’s not hard to understand why the death of that pet can be such a tragic and life altering experience. So what do you do when your best friend dies?</p>
<p>No one likes to plan for the loss of a beloved family member and pets are no exception. There are many <span style="color: #a61212;"><a style="color: #a61212;" href="http://www.aspca.org/pet-care/general-pet-care/end-life-care">resources available</a></span> to help make sure the passing is a smooth as possible for both pet and owner. Many people try and fill the void that is left by the passing of their beloved pet by adopting a similar breed in the hopes that a similar relationship can be built. Cloning your pet is like this idea only one step better.</p>
<h2 dir="LTR" align="LEFT">What Steps Are Involved?</h2>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">When you clone your pet, a piece of tissue is taken and broken down into its individual components, or cells. These cells are then used to make an identical genetic copy of your pet. In the end it is important to note that <span style="color: #a61212;"><a style="color: #a61212;" href="https://viagenpets.com/initiate-cloning/">pet cloning</a></span> is no different than selective breeding through human actions to control certain traits. Cloning is just like giving birth to an identical twin, only separated in time. While the clones cannot be guaranteed to look or behave <i>exactly</i> the same as your original companion, the similarities will be uncanny. One thing is for sure, the relationship you form with that animal will be a genuine one.</p>
<h2 dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Continuing A Special Relationship</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-1988 size-full" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/2.jpg" alt="pet cat" width="246" height="209" /></p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT"><span lang="EN">Cloning your pet means you get to start your cherished relationship over from day one and get the satisfaction of caring for that animal all over again. There are some who would say that cloning pets is unnecessary because there are so many homeless pets in need of rescue. While that is a valid point, those of us who have lost our best friends to sickness and death know that cloning our companions isn’t just to have another pet. We are doing it because we want to continue that relationship we feel was cut too short and re-form that special bond that can’t be filled by any other animal.</span></p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">That desire to bring back his friend and make his family whole again has led us to this point where <a href="https://viagenpets.com/team/">ViaGen Pets</a>, the leading company in cloning technology, can offer people the ability to re-start their relationships with their lost companions; whether dogs, cats, and horses. This technology has improved and keeps improving over time to help us reconnect families with their friends again all over the world.</p>
<ul>
<li>Dennis Milutinovich</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/pet-cloning-2/">What is Pet Cloning?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
