<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>General Archives | Viagen Pets</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.viagenpets.com/category/general/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/category/general/</link>
	<description>Love the lasts forever</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 15:44:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Plan to Clone an Extinct Horse</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/plan-clone-extinct-horse/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 15:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.viagen.com/?p=2011</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>One woman hopes technology can resurrect the Abaco Island breed. https://www.hakaimagazine.com/article-short/plan-clone-extinct-horse &#160;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/plan-clone-extinct-horse/">The Plan to Clone an Extinct Horse</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>One woman hopes technology can resurrect the Abaco Island breed.</h2>
<p>https://www.hakaimagazine.com/article-short/plan-clone-extinct-horse</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/plan-clone-extinct-horse/">The Plan to Clone an Extinct Horse</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ten Top Things We Love About Horses</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/ten-top-things-love-horses/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 21:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.viagen.com/?p=1607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ten Top Things We Love About Horses Horses keep us, and our children, out of trouble. Horses require time. Lots of it. The time committed to the care and riding of a horse, will mean less time available to wander in the mall, play video games, and other less healthy activities. Owning a horse, builds [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/ten-top-things-love-horses/">Ten Top Things We Love About Horses</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Ten Top Things We Love About Horses</strong></span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-842" src="http://www.viagen.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/viagen-equine-300x143.jpg" alt="Horse herd run in desert sand storm" width="300" height="143" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/viagen-equine-300x143.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/viagen-equine-1024x489.jpg 1024w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/viagen-equine-768x367.jpg 768w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/viagen-equine-1536x733.jpg 1536w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/viagen-equine.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<ol>
<li>Horses keep us, and our children, out of trouble.
<ul>
<li>Horses require time. Lots of it. The time committed to the care and riding of a horse, will mean less time available to wander in the mall, play video games, and other less healthy activities.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Owning a horse, builds responsibility
<ul>
<li>A horse must be fed the appropriate feed-stuffs, at controlled times of the day, in order to stay healthy.</li>
<li>They also require daily exercise.  And if they are competing, they will need LOTS of exercise.</li>
<li>These requirements mean that you must make a sizeable, scheduled time commitment in order to do both well.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>A horse allows you to meet new friends.You can belong to a saddle club, a rodeo club, a horse showing circuit, or any number of other clubs that revolve around horse riding.  You will meet friends that have a common interest….a love of horses.</li>
<li>Horses keep us humble.
<ul>
<li>When you fall off your horse (and you will), when you lose a competitive horse event, when your horse does not listen to your commands, when your saddle turns on you, because you did not cinch it up correctly….all of these things were designed by horses to keep their humans humble.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Horses keep us in shape.
<ul>
<li>All of the activities around horse ownership require significant energy expenditure – cleaning the barn, loading up trailers, tacking and riding your horse and of course, chasing them when they escape the confines of their pasture or paddock to run free.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Horses build self-confidence.
<ul>
<li>Most of the time, activity with your horse will be done alone, so it teaches you to be independent.  And the ability to get a 1000# plus animal, to perform at your bidding, is empowering and exhilarating.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Our problem solving skills and creativity are increased when we own a horse.
<ul>
<li>Every horse has their own quirks. Creative problem solving will be required for each individual in order to work through the challenges that are presented e.g. a horse unwilling to load into a trailer or cross a stream.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Horses create treasured memories.
<ul>
<li>A childhood on horseback holds the fondest memories, as you explored the frontier, raced through the ditches, and had that special bond that only a child and horse can have with each other.  You will never forget your first horse.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Horse racing is one of the most exciting sports in the world.</li>
<li>Who doesn’t remember Secretariat winning the Belmont by 31 lengths?  I still get goosebumps thinking about it.  If you are too young to remember, look it up on You Tube – there has never been another horse race like it.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>There is nothing in the world, as delightful, as the smell of a horse and the feel of the soft hair around their muzzle.</li>
<li>It is my “happy place”.</li>
</ul>
<p>There is nothing so good for the inside of a man as the outside of a horse. ~John Lubbock, &#8220;Recreation,&#8221; <em>The Use of Life</em>, 1894</p>
<p>-Diane</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/ten-top-things-love-horses/">Ten Top Things We Love About Horses</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What To Do About Dog Fight</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/what-to-do-if-dogs-fight/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 18:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dog fighting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2457</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p> What To Do About Dog Fights No matter how much we try to protect our dogs, there is always the possibility that a situation will arise that ends with a dog fight. It is important to remember that dog fights can be very dangerous for humans as well. Each fight is different and it is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/what-to-do-if-dogs-fight/">What To Do About Dog Fight</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> What To Do About Dog Fights</h1>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2458" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/dog-fight.jpg" alt="dog fight" width="1430" height="1073" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/dog-fight.jpg 1430w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/dog-fight-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/dog-fight-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/dog-fight-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1430px) 100vw, 1430px" /></p>
<p>No matter how much we try to protect our dogs, there is always the possibility that a situation will arise that ends with a dog fight. It is important to remember that dog fights can be very dangerous for humans as well. Each fight is different and it is never advisable to put yourself between any animals that are fighting. If you find yourself in the awful position of having to deal with a dog fight, assess the situation carefully before taking any action. If you do have to act in one of these situations, there are a few things to always keep in mind.</p>
<h2>Never Get Between Fighting Dogs</h2>
<p>Never get between two dogs who are fighting. It is very easy for one of them to accidentally bite a person trying to intervene. Even if you and other bystanders manage to separate any dogs who are fighting, it is quite common for a dog to become frustrated when they can’t reach the object of their aggression and redirect it to anything or anyone nearby. If you happen to be holding them back or standing closest, it makes you the easiest target.</p>
<h2>Remain Calm</h2>
<p>Try to remain as calm as possible. A lot of yelling and unnecessary activity can often only add to the stimulation and cause a dog to fight harder. Don’t forget that dogs can be very sensitive to the body language of their people and your anxiety or agitation can increase theirs.</p>
<h2>Be Careful Pulling the Leash</h2>
<p>If your dog is on a leash be aware that tugging on it or constant pulling can create an opposition reflex that may cause your dog to increase its forward aggression, rather than yielding to the pressure of the leash and turning around to leave the fight.</p>
<h2>Be Aware of Other Dogs</h2>
<p>Be aware of other dogs in your immediate area. It is often the case that when two dogs start fighting others will join in. If you see other dogs trying to join the fray, try to have their owners keep them away.</p>
<p>If a fight occurs, and is broken up, take the time to check your dog carefully for any visible wounds. Dog fights can frequently produce puncture wounds, lacerations, broken bones, and damage to eyes and ears. If you notice any such injuries, you should take your dog to a <span style="color: #a61919;"><a style="color: #a61919;" href="https://viagenpets.com/veterinarian/">veterinarian</a></span> as soon as possible where they can perform an exam and ascertain the extent of the damage.</p>
<p>Many dog fights can be avoided simply by paying close attention to your dog and those around you. If you pay attention to the warning signals that indicate your dog is becoming agitated or nervous about another dog, you may be able to avert a potentially dangerous situation and continue to enjoy whatever activity you are happily engaged in.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/what-to-do-if-dogs-fight/">What To Do About Dog Fight</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aging Pets Need Special Attention</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/aging-pets-need-special-attention/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 15:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aging pets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Caring For Your Aging Pet Aging in pets happens.  We all know that bringing home a fluffy kitten or bouncing puppy can be a momentous event and that will entail changes and lifestyle adjustments for everyone involved. What is often overlooked, however, are the adjustments necessary to properly care for an aging pet. According to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/aging-pets-need-special-attention/">Aging Pets Need Special Attention</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Caring For Your Aging Pet</h1>
<p>Aging in pets happens.  We all know that bringing home a fluffy kitten or bouncing puppy can be a momentous event and that will entail changes and lifestyle adjustments for everyone involved. What is often overlooked, however, are the adjustments necessary to properly care for an aging pet. According to the <span style="color: #8c0f0f;"><a style="color: #8c0f0f;" href="https://www.avma.org/public/PetCare/Pages/Caring-for-an-Older-Pet-FAQs.aspx" target="_blank">American Veterinary Medical Association</a></span> cats and small dogs are considered seniors at the age of 7 while larger dog breeds enter their geriatric years at age 6. Just like in people, there are many small changes that can be made to help ease some of the stressors a beloved puppy or kitten might encounter as they enter their twilight years.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2430" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/senior-dog-e1353361879372.jpg" alt="aging dog" width="472" height="285" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/senior-dog-e1353361879372.jpg 472w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/senior-dog-e1353361879372-300x181.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 472px) 100vw, 472px" /></p>
<h2>Diet And Exercise for Older Pets</h2>
<p>One of the most important considerations for older cats and dogs is their diet and body condition. Consider switching your dog or cat to a diet made specifically for senior pets and consult your veterinarian about your pet’s body condition. Having an appropriate weight can play a large role in joint health and general well-being. Also, ongoing exercise is great for older pets but be aware that stamina and energy may decrease even if their desire to please and keep going the extra mile won’t. It will be up to you as their pet parent to make sure they stop an activity when they should but that shouldn’t mean that your favorite game of fetch or chase the feather is off limits.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Veterinarians Are Important</h2>
<p>Another great way to ensure the health of a senior pet is to take them to a <span style="color: #8c0f0f;"><a style="color: #8c0f0f;" href="https://viagenpets.com/veterinarian/">veterinarian</a></span> for regular visits. A veterinarian can monitor the health or your cat or dog and make recommendations for any necessary changes in diet, exercise, or extra supplementation to address specific issues such as joint pain or skin and coat dullness. Regular health exams also play a vital role in catching issues like kidney or heart disease early enough to initiate preventive treatment. Older pets can also be more susceptible to diabetes or certain cancers and a veterinarian can help detect and treat these and other similar diseases that threaten to shorten your time with your beloved companion.</p>
<p>Dental health is another often overlooked area. Periodontal disease in dogs and cats can be just a big a risk as it is in people, causing detrimental changes to heart, liver, and kidney muscles. Though prevention for dental issues should start before a pet is technically considered a senior, continued vigilance in the dental hygiene of older cats and dogs is crucial to their health. More information about <a href="https://www.avma.org/public/PetCare/Pages/Pet-Dental-Care.aspx" target="_blank"><span style="color: #8c0f0f;">dental care can be found here</span></a>.</p>
<p>If you are ever in doubt about how to care for an aging companion you should not hesitate to contact your local veterinarian. The more information you have the better prepared you will be to make your friend’s transition into old age as easy and comfortable as possible. We all want as many wonderful years as possible with our furry friends and a few small changes are all it takes to ensure as many happy moments as possible with them.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/aging-pets-need-special-attention/">Aging Pets Need Special Attention</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top Ten Reasons We Love Dogs</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/top-ten-reasons-we-love-dogs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 22:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dog qualities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2358</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Here Are The Top Ten Reasons We Love Dogs Dog owners are, shall we say, a special breed.  We share that special love of dogs and know how important they are to our lives.  But why, exactly do we love dogs so much?  There are a lot of answers to this question (and unique ones [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/top-ten-reasons-we-love-dogs/">Top Ten Reasons We Love Dogs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Here Are The Top Ten Reasons We Love Dogs</h1>
<p>Dog owners are, shall we say, a special breed.  We share that special love of dogs and know how important they are to our lives.  But why, exactly do we love dogs so much?  There are a lot of answers to this question (and unique ones for each dog!), but here are the top ten.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>1. Loyalty</h2>
<p><em>I know well enough that there have been dogs so loving that they have thrown themselves into the same grave with the dead bodies of their masters; others have stayed upon their masters&#8217; graves without stirring a moment from them, and have voluntarily starved themselves to death, refusing to touch the food that was brought them.</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Miguel de Cervantes</em></li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-2359 size-full" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/d1.jpg" alt="Dog and Dog Owner in Car" width="604" height="333" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/d1.jpg 604w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/d1-300x165.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 604px) 100vw, 604px" /></p>
<p>There are some that would say a dog is only loyal so long as it is getting food and shelter. But if you have ever known a dog and seen the reaction it has when you come home or it is reunited with a fellow four legged friend you know it is about more than that. There are plenty of examples of dogs showing loyalty to their owners. Some of the most famous are the dog pictured lying next to the casket of his Navy Seal owner, or the dog that would greet his owner at the train station every day after he arrived home from work. Even after the owner died, this dog, Hachiko, went to the station every day for the next nine years waiting for the arrival of his best friend.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>2. Friendship</h2>
<p><em>Thorns may hurt you, men desert you, sunlight turn to fog; but you&#8217;re never friendless ever, if you have a dog.</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Douglas Mallock</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Dogs have been human’s best friends for thousands of years. They are there for us through thick and thin. They never judge and are always happy to see us return, whether we’ve been gone five hours or five minutes.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>3. Therapy</h2>
<p><em>I have found that when you are deeply troubled, there are things you get from the silent devoted companionship of a dog that you can get from no other source.</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Doris Day</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Animal-assisted therapy has been linked to the reduction of anxiety, pain, and depression in people with a range of <span style="color: #941212;"><a style="color: #941212;" href="http://www.mayoclinic.org/healthy-living/consumer-health/in-depth/pet-therapy/art-20046342?pg=2" target="_blank">mental or physical health problems</a></span>. Many people can benefit from pet therapy, including patients undergoing chemotherapy, veterans with post-traumatic stress disorder, and physical therapy patients working on their fine motor skills. Even students can take advantage of pet therapy that alleviates feelings of homesickness and depression.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>4. Health</h2>
<p><em>People who keep dogs live longer on average than those who do not. This is not some kind of pro-canine campaigning fantasy. It is a simple medical fact that the calming influence of the company of a friendly pet animal reduces blood pressure and therefore the risk of heart attack.</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Desmond Morris</em></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="color: #941212;"><a style="color: #941212;" href="http://www.webmd.com/hypertension-high-blood-pressure/features/6-ways-pets-improve-your-health#1" target="_blank">There are many ways that having a dog is good for our health.</a></span> People with dogs are shown to have less heart problems because they get regular exercise from walking their pets. Having a dog improves our mood and reduces stress which in turn means lower blood pressure. Spending just 15-30 minutes with your dog can help you feel more calm and relaxed, reducing stress and increasing happiness. Playing with your pup increases your brain’s levels of dopamine and serotonin, both of which are neurotransmitters associated with pleasure and tranquility. Dogs even seem to be able to <span style="color: #941212;"><a style="color: #941212;" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/25/dogs-smell-cancer_n_3142135.html" target="_blank">detect the smell of cancer in humans</a></span>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>5. Unconditional Love</h2>
<p><em>A dog is the only thing on this earth that loves you more than he loves himself.</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Josh Billings (Henry Wheeler Shaw)</em></li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-2360" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/d2.jpg" alt="cut pet bull dog" width="300" height="592" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/d2.jpg 461w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/d2-152x300.jpg 152w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/d2-300x592.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>It’s easy to see with the wagging and happy barking when we come home that our dogs love us. Scientists have recently proven that dogs love us back the same way we love them by <span style="color: #941212;"><a style="color: #941212;" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-2546493/Your-dog-really-does-love-Research-finds-brain-associated-affection-similar-pets-humans.html" target="_blank">scanning their brains in an MRI machine</a></span>. Those body wiggles aren’t just because he is excited for food (but it’s probably safe to say that’s a part of it).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>6. Protection</h2>
<p><em>The nose of the bulldog has been slanted backwards so that he can breathe without letting go.</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Winston Churchill</em></li>
</ul>
<p>It is believed that man’s first interactions with dogs (wolves at the time) resulted in a beneficial relationship for both species. The wolves got easy pickings from the scraps that people left behind after their meals and people got the benefit of having the wolves around to protect them from any other predators that may prey on those people. In more recent times, dogs were <span style="color: #941212;"><a style="color: #941212;" href="http://www.petmd.com/dog/pet_lover/evr_dg_military_dog" target="_blank">trained by the military as sentry guards</a></span>, protecting troops from attack. And as silent scouts, dogs would warn troops to the presence of enemies, diminishing the chances of an ambush. The troops lucky enough to have these attack dogs by their sides were most likely to survive war. From puppyhood, dogs innately learn to watch and be aware of anything rotten coming your way. Potential burglars are put off by a barking or watching dog in the window.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>7. Selflessness</h2>
<p><em>It don&#8217;t care whether I&#8217;m good enough. It don&#8217;t care whether I snore or not. It don&#8217;t care which God I pray to. There are only three things with that kind of unconditional acceptance: Dogs, donuts, and money.</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Danny DeVito</em> as Lawrence Garfield in <em>Other People&#8217;s Money</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Your dog never lies to you when he says he loves you. The more you give of yourself, the better the connection developed between the two of you. There is nothing better than coming home from a very hard day at work or maybe school or college and find your dog there waiting for you to support you.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>8. Exercise</h2>
<p><em>Golf seems to be an arduous way to go for a walk. I prefer to take the dogs out.</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Princess Anne</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Dogs requires daily exercise, and we do to. Dog owners carry the responsibility of playing with and working their dogs, so it only makes sense that dog people tend to be more active. One study found that dog owners were 34 percent more likely to achieve their recommended 150 minutes of exercise per week than non-dog owners.</p>
<h2></h2>
<h2>9. Forgiveness</h2>
<p><em>My dogs forgive anger in me, the arrogance in me, the brute in me. They forgive everything I do before I forgive myself.</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Guy de la Valdene</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Dogs don&#8217;t hold grudges. They don&#8217;t hang on to what someone said years ago. When one of them plays too rough, the other dog lets them know immediately by letting out a yelp. The two dogs make up and instantly start playing again.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>10. Happiness</h2>
<p><em>The great pleasure of a dog is that you may make a fool of yourself with him and not only will he not scold you, but he will make a fool of himself too.</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Samuel Butler, </em><em>Higgledy-Piggledy</em></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/top-ten-reasons-we-love-dogs/">Top Ten Reasons We Love Dogs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Key In Dog Nutrition?</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/what-is-key-in-dog-nutrition/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 19:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dog nutrition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Dog Nutrition Essentials Dog nutrition isn&#8217;t necessarily a topic we think of everyday, but if you want your dog to live the longest, healthiest life possible your dog’s balanced nutrition is essential.   It&#8217;s critical in maintaining the growth and health of your dog. So what does this mean? First of all, what are nutrients? Nutrients are substances [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/what-is-key-in-dog-nutrition/">What is Key In Dog Nutrition?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1><strong>Dog Nutrition Essentials</strong></h1>
<p>Dog nutrition isn&#8217;t necessarily a topic we think of everyday, but if you want your dog to live the longest, healthiest life possible your dog’s balanced nutrition is essential.   It&#8217;s critical in maintaining the growth and health of your dog. So what does this mean?</p>
<p>First of all, what are nutrients? Nutrients are substances obtained in food and used by an animal as a source of energy, maintenance and growth. There are 6 types of nutrients dogs need to optimize their health.</p>
<h2><b><strong>1.WATER</strong></b></h2>
<p>All dogs needs water to survive. More than half of an adult dog’s body weight is water. While some food may help with your dog’s water needs, it still is not enough. There should always be fresh clean water available to them.</p>
<h2><b><strong>2. PROTEIN</strong></b></h2>
<div id="attachment_2334" style="width: 208px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2334" class="size-full wp-image-2334" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/dog.jpg" alt="dog eating dog nutrition" width="198" height="254" /><p id="caption-attachment-2334" class="wp-caption-text">MMM&#8230;Protein!</p></div>
<p>Proteins are a source of energy that are essential for growth, maintenance, reproduction, and repair. They can be animal-based meats, vegetables, cereals and soy. As long as the type of diet contains sufficient protein, it does not matter if you choose a meat based diet or a vegetarian based diet.</p>
<h2><b><strong>3. FATS</strong></b></h2>
<p>Fats provide your dog with the most energy and are the most concentrated form of food energy. They also play a vital role in the structure of cells and help maintain healthy skin and a glossy hair coat.</p>
<h2><b><strong>4. CARBORHYDRATES</strong></b></h2>
<p>In addition to providing energy, carbohydrates are beneficial for reproduction and the healthy maintenance of the intestine. The major sources of carbohydrates in commercial dog foods are cereals, legumes, and other plant foodstuffs.</p>
<h2><b><strong>5. VITAMINS</strong></b></h2>
<p>Vitamins cannot be synthesized in the body, therefore they are important to obtain in the diet. Only tiny amounts of vitamins are needed and if you are feeding your dog a complete and balanced diet, vitamin supplements are unnecessary unless specified by a veterinarian.</p>
<h2><strong>6. MINERALS</strong></h2>
<p>Overall, there are twelve minerals known to be vital nutrients for dogs. For example, calcium and phosphorus are essential for strong bones and teeth. See the National Research Council guideline for a <span style="color: #9c1616;"><a style="color: #9c1616;" href="https://www.nap.edu/catalog/10668/nutrient-requirements-of-dogs-and-cats" target="_blank">complete list</a></span>.</p>
<h2><strong>GUIDELINES WHEN PURCHASING COMMERICAL DOG FOOD:</strong></h2>
<p>*High quality named animal proteins should be the first ingredient, and preferably appear more than once as a top item on the ingredient list.</p>
<p>*Pick foods that include the whole fruit, vegetable, or grain. For example, rice rather than rice flour.</p>
<p>*Select ingredients with natural preservatives (like Vitamin C) or antioxidants (like rosemary extract).</p>
<p>*Avoid foods that use generic descriptions. For example, “meat” meal or “animal” fat. The actual type of meat or fat needs to be named.</p>
<p>*Avoid all by-products, added sweeteners, artificial preservatives and artificial flavors/colors.</p>
<p>The amount you feed your dog should be based on size, age, and energy productivity. For example, puppies require the most calories per day and inactive adult dogs require the least caloric intake per day. Treats should be given in moderation and should represent a small percentage of the dog’s daily intake. Use the same food guidelines when choosing your dog’s treats. It is recommended dogs be fed twice daily, but you should always consult with your veterinarian to determine the best feeding schedule and the best types of foods for your dog. Using a proper balance of the 6 nutrients discussed will enable your dog to live the healthiest life.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/what-is-key-in-dog-nutrition/">What is Key In Dog Nutrition?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Relationships Does ViaGen Pets Have With Our Clients?</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/relationships-viagen-pets-clients/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 15:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>ViaGen Pets and Our Pet Owners In your time as a client, you may only speak to a few of the employees that help to make ViaGen Pets a possibility. It may be comforting to know that many of us are pet parents… just like you. We feel the loss you are experiencing when a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/relationships-viagen-pets-clients/">What Relationships Does ViaGen Pets Have With Our Clients?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 dir="LTR" align="LEFT">ViaGen Pets and Our Pet Owners</h1>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">In your time as a client, you may only speak to a few of the employees that help to make ViaGen Pets a possibility. It may be comforting to know that many of us are pet parents… just like you. We feel the loss you are experiencing when a beloved pet dies, and we feel your joy and excitement when you pick up your new cloned puppy or kitten.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">At ViaGen Pets, we recognize that you have a unique history with your pet that makes them family members. We are here to learn more about that relationship and help you, the client, honor those memories by preserving your pet’s genetics. Your relationship with ViaGen Pets will begin with a conversation with Melain or Codi, who are experts on the ViaGen Pets Client Services Team. They will respond to your inquiry if it is sent <a href="https://viagenpets.com/request-information/"><span style="color: #a10d0d;">through the website.</span></a>  <span style="font-family: Calibri;"> </span></p>
<h2 dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Our Pet Owners Are Guided Throughout The Process</h2>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">These capable team members will assist you in determining which preservation service (<span style="color: #a10d0d;"><a style="color: #a10d0d;" href="https://viagenpets.com/product/genetic-preservation/">Genetic Preservation</a></span> or <span style="color: #a10d0d;"><a style="color: #a10d0d;" href="https://viagenpets.com/product/express-tissue-banking/">Express Tissue Banking</a></span>) will be best for your situation.  The team will be there to assist you from the time you order your biopsy kit, to the time your pet&#8217;s cell culture has been completed.  They will keep you updated with tracking information, let you know when the biopsy samples have arrived at our office and contact you with the final results that confirm that your pet&#8217;s cells are safely preserved.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"> </span></span></p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"><span lang="EN"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-2309" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/DSC_0259b.jpg" alt="viagen pets clients" width="600" height="336" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/DSC_0259b.jpg 2261w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/DSC_0259b-300x168.jpg 300w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/DSC_0259b-1024x574.jpg 1024w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/DSC_0259b-768x430.jpg 768w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/DSC_0259b-1536x861.jpg 1536w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/DSC_0259b-2048x1148.jpg 2048w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></span></span></span></p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">After the preservation service for your pet has been completed, the client service team will keep you up-to-date with the latest ViaGen Pets news through our social media pages and newsletter. Of course, you can always contact one of the experts on the ViaGen Pets team if you have questions about your pet’s cells or if you would like to discuss plans to move forward with pet cloning.</p>
<h2 dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Coordination With Our Animal Care Director</h2>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">Once you have made the decision to move forward with the pet cloning process, you will continue to work with the Client Services team and our Animal Care Director, Leslie. She will customize aspects of the process to best fit the needs of your puppy or kitten and we will keep you informed of your pet’s progress.</p>
<p dir="LTR" align="LEFT">We are here to help you preserve your beloved pet&#8217;s genetics, but we also value the relationships we form with our clients and their pets.  We treasure receiving pet photos and particularly appreciate the cherished memories you are willing to share about your pet.  If you are a client that has preserved your pet&#8217;s genetics, you can share your pet&#8217;s story and photo <span style="color: #a10d0d;"><a style="color: #a10d0d;" href="https://viagenpets.com/submit-your-viagen-pets-story/" target="_blank">here.</a></span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/relationships-viagen-pets-clients/">What Relationships Does ViaGen Pets Have With Our Clients?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Dog Days of Summer:  Summer Hazards and Your Pet</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/pets-summer-hazards/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 19:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summer hazards pet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Summer Can Pose Unique Pet Risks Attention all pet parents: it’s summertime!  (Trust us, nobody has forgotten this in Central Texas recently!) That means we are outside more enjoying swimming, hiking, boating, having picnics, gardening, taking walks, etc. Many of these fun times include our furry friends, our dogs and cats. Unfortunately, there are many [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/pets-summer-hazards/">The Dog Days of Summer:  Summer Hazards and Your Pet</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Summer Can Pose Unique Pet Risks</h1>
<p>Attention all pet parents: it’s summertime!  (Trust us, nobody has forgotten this in Central Texas recently!) That means we are outside more enjoying swimming, hiking, boating, having picnics, gardening, taking walks, etc. Many of these fun times include our furry friends, our dogs and cats. Unfortunately, there are many hazards to our pets that we might not even know of or have forgotten about.</p>
<h2>Pet Threat #1: Sun and Heat</h2>
<p>Avoid walking your dog outside during the hottest parts of the day. The pavement is hot and can easily burn the paw pads on your dog. If you notice them limping, refusing to walk, licking or chewing at their feet, blisters and or redness these are all signs of burned pads. Save your walks for early morning or in the evening after the sun is going down.</p>
<p>Leaving animals in hot cars. You may not realize just how hot your car actually gets so leaving your pet in a hot car for any period of time is not a good practice.   Below is graphic that shows you how long it takes for your car to heat up and become lethal to your pet.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-2257 size-full" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/hot-car-temperatures.png" alt="pets and hot car temperatures" width="616" height="588" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/hot-car-temperatures.png 616w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/hot-car-temperatures-300x286.png 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 616px) 100vw, 616px" /></p>
<p>It’s hot outside! Be sure that your furry friend has plenty of water available to stay hydrated. Just like us humans they need water to help regulate our body temperature. <em>Remember if it’s hot for you it’s hot for your pet too.</em></p>
<h2>More Pet Threats To Watch Out For: Other Animals, Snakes and Bees</h2>
<p>With the warmer weather most of us venture outside more with our pets. Perhaps you take your dog to a local dog park. It’s really important to be observant while at your dog park as not all dogs are social and not all owners are aware of that. It’s possible to encounter an aggressive dog, an anti-social dog or that innocent sniff sparks a quick and ugly fight. Be alert! It’s also important while at dog parks and walking your pet that you keep a close eye out for poop from other pets. You certainly don’t want your dog to eat someone else’s poop. Not only is that really nasty but it can also spread germs, worms, disease, etc.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-2258 size-full" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/I_love_my_pet.png" alt="I_love_my_pet" width="562" height="307" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/I_love_my_pet.png 562w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/I_love_my_pet-300x164.png 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 562px) 100vw, 562px" /></p>
<p>No matter where you live there are snakes. Many snakes are hard to see until you are right up on them. It’s super important to be observant of your surroundings at all times for your safety and the safety of your pet. Dogs use their nose to explore and unfortunately that is typically the right spot for a hidden snake to strike. Just like humans many animals can be allergic to venom so it’s really important to act quickly if your dog is bitten.</p>
<p>Don’t forget that bees are also dangerous to pets. Just like a possible snake bite pets could also be allergic to a bee sting. Many sites I visited suggested carrying Benadryl with you if you are going camping or on a hike that you can quickly access if your pet gets stung and starts showing an allergic reaction. Although that is a great idea it’s best to speak with your veterinarian first to understand the proper dosage for the age and size of your pet.</p>
<h2></h2>
<h2>Be Mindful Around Pools and Water</h2>
<p>If your dog is anything like mine, you can’t keep her out of the pool. Even though I have a lab, who is a great swimmer, there are several things to consider before allowing your dog to swim. Don’t just let your dog get in the water unsupervised. Make sure your dog is aware of all entry and exist points in the pool and ensure they know how to get in and out. It’s also best to keep all entry and exist points clear of furniture, toys, etc. that might make it hard for a pet to get out of the water safely.</p>
<p>So many of the plants we have in and outside of our homes are dangerous to both cats and dogs. There are so many in fact that I cannot even list them. For a comprehensive list of <span style="color: #9e1111;"><a style="color: #9e1111;" href="http://www.tica.org/cat-health" target="_blank">plants dangerous to cats please check out this site from TICA</a> </span>and for <span style="color: #9e1111;"><a style="color: #9e1111;" href="http://www.aspca.org/pet-care/animal-poison-control/toxic-and-non-toxic-plants" target="_blank">dogs please check out this page on the ASPCA site</a></span>.</p>
<h2>Final Summer Pet Threat: Food</h2>
<p>Many common foods that we eat during summer are dangerous and even lethal to our furry babies. Think twice before you push those crumbs on the floor or don’t pick up something you dropped. Here is a list of just a few of the common food items around our home that are harmful to our pets.</p>
<p>In dogs these include: alcohol, avocado, chocolate, coffee, garlic, grapes, macadamia nuts, onions, raisins, fruit pits and seeds and corn cobs and bones that can cause an obstruction.</p>
<p>In cats these include: alcohol, onions, garlic and root vegetables, green tomatoes, raw potatoes, chocolate, grapes, raisins and avocado.</p>
<p>Bottom line, love your pet well and be smart and aware of the dangers in and outside of your home.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/pets-summer-hazards/">The Dog Days of Summer:  Summer Hazards and Your Pet</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Are Regular Vet Visits Important for Dogs?</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/regular-vet-visits-important-dogs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 20:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veterinarians]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2065</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Vet Visits For Your Dog Are Critical If ain’t broke don’t fix it, right? This is often the case with most things. But with preventative care for your beloved dog it is oftentimes better than dealing with a critical health issue that was ignored. There are things that your dog could be experiencing quietly that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/regular-vet-visits-important-dogs/">Why Are Regular Vet Visits Important for Dogs?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Vet Visits For Your Dog Are Critical</h1>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-2066 size-full" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/june-blog-pic.jpg" alt="dog veterinarian picture" width="236" height="206" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/june-blog-pic.jpg 236w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/june-blog-pic-235x206.jpg 235w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 236px) 100vw, 236px" /></p>
<p>If ain’t broke don’t fix it, right? This is often the case with most things. But with preventative care for your beloved dog it is oftentimes better than dealing with a critical health issue that was ignored. There are things that <span style="color: #910d0d;"><a style="color: #910d0d;" href="https://viagenpets.com/dog-cloning/">your dog</a></span> could be experiencing quietly that go unnoticed. With regular checkups, your vet can look for subtle signs and symptoms. If caught early enough the fix is usually easier than trying to do damage repair.</p>
<h2>Heartworms and Gingivitis Are Regular Canine Health Issues</h2>
<p>One example is heartworms. This disease is spread by infected mosquitoes and there is no way to know which mosquitoes are infected therefore prevention is key. Regular checkups, blood tests and preventative medication are critical to your dog’s health in avoiding this deadly disease. These prevention methods are by far a better option than subjecting your dog to injection treatments if they have heartworms.</p>
<p>Another example is gingivitis. Gingivitis is a disease that occurs when bacteria accumulates along the gum line. This is currently one of the most common diseases in dogs. Stage 1 gingivitis in your dog can be much more easily treated than allowing this disease to progress to Stage 2, 3 or 4. The progression of this disease leads to bone loss in the jaw and teeth which then will affect their diet and lead to deteriorating health. Regular checkups can help your vet to determine the early stages of the onset of gingivitis or any other kind of periodontal disease which can then be addressed immediately.</p>
<p>There are many other ailments that dogs need to have regularly checked including bone and joint issues which can affect mobility and exercise, skin issues that are caused by allergies and many other things that your vet knows to look for. Remember one minute today can save you a lot of heartache tomorrow.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Here is a <span style="color: #910d0d;"><a style="color: #910d0d;" href="http://www.dogster.com/dog-health-care/vet-checklist-dogs-first-visit" target="_blank">great checklist</a></span> when taking your dog to the vet.  And here&#8217;s a <span style="color: #910d0d;"><a style="color: #910d0d;" href="ttp://www.petmd.com/cat/care/evr_ct_cat_vet_visit_checklist#" target="_blank">great checklist </a></span>for all you cat parents.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/regular-vet-visits-important-dogs/">Why Are Regular Vet Visits Important for Dogs?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pet Memorial Day: Ten Ways to Memorialize Your Pet</title>
		<link>https://www.viagenpets.com/national-pet-memorial-day-ten-ways-memorialize-pet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VP Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 23:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pet memorial day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://viagenpets.com/?p=2059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Remembering Your Deceased Pet &#160; Pet Memorial Day deals with an issue that as pet parents we all know is coming. We all dread it just the same. At some point our beloved four legged companion is going to cross the Rainbow Bridge. I hate to even think about it because thinking about it makes it [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/national-pet-memorial-day-ten-ways-memorialize-pet/">Pet Memorial Day: Ten Ways to Memorialize Your Pet</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Remembering Your Deceased Pet</h1>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2060" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/IMG_6848.jpg" alt="pet memorial day photo" width="604" height="479" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/IMG_6848.jpg 604w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/IMG_6848-300x238.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 604px) 100vw, 604px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Pet Memorial Day deals with an issue that as pet parents we all know is coming. We all dread it just the same. At some point our beloved four legged companion is going to cross the Rainbow Bridge. I hate to even think about it because thinking about it makes it real. Honestly, I don’t want it to be real. Not now. Not ever.</p>
<p>I have had Coco, my sweet Chocolate Lab, for thirteen years. My husband and I met her only a few days after she was born and the gracious breeder allowed us and really encouraged us to visit with her weekly until she could come home with us. We experienced so many firsts right along with her. She immediately bonded with us as much as we did to her.</p>
<p>For thirteen years this dog&#8211;no, this friend of mine&#8211;has been the most loyal companion I could ever ask for. No matter the kind of day I was having; no matter how mad, sad, or happy I was, Coco was always thrilled to greet me at the door, give me a kiss, shake my hand, snuggle or lick away my tears. She has provided me with the most unconditional love that maybe I have ever known. Over the years Coco has extended that same love to really everyone that has ever crossed her path.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2061" src="https://viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/IMG_6847.jpg" alt="pet memorial day photo" width="480" height="604" srcset="https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/IMG_6847.jpg 480w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/IMG_6847-238x300.jpg 238w, https://www.viagenpets.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/IMG_6847-300x378.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px" /></p>
<h2>Ten Ways To Memorialize Your Pet</h2>
<p>How is it even possible for me to memorialize such an amazing kindness in my life? Could I even do her justice? Would I even make her proud? Would anyone else even care or get it? Maybe I am just plain nuts? Even though it’s not Coco’s time, and hopefully isn’t for a long time, I am going to prepare myself just the same.</p>
<p>Here are 10 ways to memorialize your pet that I found interesting.</p>
<p>1. The Pet Bio Urn made by Cast Paper Art. I actually met these very nice folks at Western Veterinary Conference 2016 and brought a sample home. You can visit <span style="color: #851111;"><a style="color: #851111;" href="http://www.castpaperart.com/seed-paper/pet-bio-urn-95-cubic-inches/" target="_blank">Pet Bio Urn here</a></span>.</p>
<p>2. A tattoo with specific significance to your fur baby.</p>
<p>3. A custom pet nose print necklace such as<a href="http://www.uncommongoods.com/product/custom-pet-nose-print-necklaces" target="_blank"><span style="color: #851111;"> this one at Uncommon Goods</span></a>.</p>
<p>4. An exact <span style="color: #851111;"><a style="color: #851111;" href="http://www.cuddleclones.com/" target="_blank">replica of your pet from Cuddle Clones</a></span>.</p>
<p>5. Engrave a river stone with your pet’s name or create a concrete stepping stone.</p>
<p>6. Create a shadow box and include items like: collar, favorite toy, pictures, etc.</p>
<p>7. A professional pet portrait.</p>
<p>8. Plant a tree in their honor.</p>
<p>9. Turn their ashes into fireworks.</p>
<p><span style="color: #851111;"><span style="color: #000000;">10.</span><a style="color: #851111;" href="https://viagenpets.com/product/genetic-preservation/"> Genetic preservation</a></span> of their tissue through ViaGen Pets.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Memorializing Your Pet Is A Personal Decision</h2>
<p>Trust me, there are endless possibilities available for all of us to memorialize our pet. Bottom line, it’s a very personal decision. Don’t allow anyone to shame you if you feel the need to extend your bond and connection. Do your homework, take your time and you will make the right decision for you and your pet. No matter what way you choose to memorialize your pet you will always have the fondest memories in your heart for a lifetime.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com/national-pet-memorial-day-ten-ways-memorialize-pet/">Pet Memorial Day: Ten Ways to Memorialize Your Pet</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.viagenpets.com">Viagen Pets</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
